<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 09:04:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Anti-Bias AI Order Is Just More Bias</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/trump-ai-order-bias-openai-google/</link>
      <description>The Trump administration says it wants AI models free from ideological bias, as it pressures their developers to reflect the president’s worldview.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/trump-ai-order-bias-openai-google/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic deploys AI agents to audit models for safety</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/anthropic-deploys-ai-agents-audit-models-for-safety/</link>
      <description>Anthropic has built an army of autonomous AI agents with a singular mission: to audit powerful models like Claude to improve safety. As these complex systems rapidly advance, the job of making sure they are safe and don’t harbour hidden dangers has become a herculean task. Anthropic believes it has found a solution, and it’s […]
The post Anthropic deploys AI agents to audit models for safety appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 13:40:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/anthropic-deploys-ai-agents-audit-models-for-safety/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alibaba’s new Qwen reasoning AI model sets open-source records</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/alibaba-new-qwen-reasoning-ai-model-open-source-records/</link>
      <description>The Qwen team from Alibaba have just released a new version of their open-source reasoning AI model with some impressive benchmarks. Meet Qwen3-235B-A22B-Thinking-2507. Over the past three months, the Qwen team has been hard at work scaling up what they call the “thinking capability” of their AI, aiming to improve both the quality and depth […]
The post Alibaba’s new Qwen reasoning AI model sets open-source records appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 12:43:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/alibaba-new-qwen-reasoning-ai-model-open-source-records/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cursor’s New Bugbot Is Designed to Save Vibe Coders From Themselves</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/cursor-releases-new-ai-tool-for-debugging-code/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 15:00:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/cursor-releases-new-ai-tool-for-debugging-code/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Says He’s ‘Getting Rid of Woke’ and Dismisses Copyright Concerns in AI Policy Speech</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/president-trump-ai-action-plan-speech/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 22:11:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/president-trump-ai-action-plan-speech/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Action Plan: US leadership must be ‘unchallenged’</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-action-plan-us-leadership-must-be-unchallenged/</link>
      <description>The White House has released its ‘AI Action Plan’, which frames the coming decade as a technological race the US cannot afford to lose. Laced with the urgent rhetoric of a new cold war, the action plan argues that securing victory in AI is nothing short of a national imperative. Trump’s foreword sets the tone, […]
The post AI Action Plan: US leadership must be ‘unchallenged’ appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 16:20:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-action-plan-us-leadership-must-be-unchallenged/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s AI Action Plan Is a Crusade Against ‘Bias’—and Regulation</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/trumps-ai-action-plan-crusade-against-bias-regulation/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 14:52:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/trumps-ai-action-plan-crusade-against-bias-regulation/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Era for WIRED—That Starts With You</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-era-for-wired-that-starts-with-you/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-era-for-wired-that-starts-with-you/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sam Altman: AI will cause job losses and national security threats</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/sam-altman-ai-cause-job-losses-national-security-threats/</link>
      <description>In the halls of power in Washington, OpenAI’s chief, Sam Altman, warned of total job losses from AI and how national security is being rewritten. Altman positions OpenAI as not just a participant, but as the essential architect of our destiny. Holding court at the Federal Reserve’s conference for large banks, Altman clearly stated how […]
The post Sam Altman: AI will cause job losses and national security threats appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 10:57:29 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/sam-altman-ai-cause-job-losses-national-security-threats/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Seeks Additional Capital From Investors as Part of Its $40 Billion Round</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-fundraising-round-softbank-sam-altman/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 18:23:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-fundraising-round-softbank-sam-altman/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google’s newest Gemini 2.5 model aims for ‘intelligence per dollar’</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/googles-newest-gemini-2-5-model-aims-intelligence-per-dollar/</link>
      <description>Google just dropped the stable version of Gemini 2.5 Flash-Lite and they’ve essentially created a model that’s designed to be the workhorse for developers who need to build things at scale without breaking the bank.Building cool things with AI can often feel like a frustrating balancing act. You want a model that’s smart and powerful, but you also don’t want to remortgage your house to pay for the API calls. And if your app needs to be fast for users, a slow, churning model is a non-starter.Google says Gemini 2.5 Flash-Lite is quicker than their previous speedy models, which is a big claim. For anyone building a real-time translator, a customer service chatbot, or anything where a lag would feel awkward, this is huge.And then there’s the price. At $0.10 to process a million words of input and $0.40 for the output, it’s ridiculously cheap. This is the kind of pricing that changes how you think about development. You can finally stop worrying about every single API call and just let your application do its thing. It opens the door for small teams and solo developers to build things that were previously only viable for big companies.Now, you might be thinking, “Okay, it’s cheap and fast, so it must be a bit dim-witted, right?” Apparently not. Google insists the Gemini 2.5 Flash-Lite model is smarter than its predecessors across the board: reasoning, coding, and even understanding images and audio.Of course, it still has that massive one million token context window—that means you can throw huge documents, codebases, or long transcripts at it and it won’t break a sweat.And this isn’t just marketing fluff, companies are already building things with it.Space tech company Satlyt is using it on satellites to diagnose problems in orbit, cutting down on delays and saving power. Another one, HeyGen, is using it to translate videos into over 180 languages.A personal favourite example is DocsHound. They use it to watch product demo videos and automatically create technical documentation from them. Imagine how much time that saves! It shows that Flash-Lite is more than capable of handling complex, real-world tasks.If you want to try out the Gemini 2.5 Flash-Lite model, you can start using it now in Google AI Studio or Vertex AI. All you have to do is specify “gemini-2.5-...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 17:02:58 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/googles-newest-gemini-2-5-model-aims-intelligence-per-dollar/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI and Oracle announce Stargate AI data centre deal</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-and-oracle-announce-stargate-ai-data-centre-deal/</link>
      <description>OpenAI has shaken hands with Oracle on a colossal deal to advance the former’s colossal Stargate AI data centre initiative.It’s one thing to talk about the AI revolution in abstract terms, but it’s another thing entirely to grasp the sheer physical scale of what’s being built to make it happen. The foundations of our AI future are being laid in concrete, steel, and miles of fibre-optic cable, and those foundations are getting colossally bigger.Together, OpenAI and Oracle are going to build new data centres in the US packed with enough hardware to consume 4.5 gigawatts of power. It’s hard to overstate what a staggering amount of energy that is—it’s the kind of power that could light up a major city. And all of it will be dedicated to one thing: powering the next generation of AI.This isn’t just a random expansion; it’s a huge piece of OpenAI’s grand Stargate plan. The goal is simple: to build enough computing power to bring advanced AI to everyone.When you add this new project to the work already underway in Abilene, Texas, OpenAI is now developing over 5 gigawatts of data centre capacity. That’s enough space to run more than two million of the most powerful computer chips available.This move shows they are dead serious about a pledge they made at the White House earlier this year to plough half a trillion dollars into US AI infrastructure. In fact, with the momentum they’re getting from partners like Oracle and Japan’s SoftBank, they now expect to blow past that initial goal.But this story isn’t just about silicon chips and corporate deals; it’s about people. OpenAI believes that building and running these new Stargate AI data centres will create over 100,000 jobs.That job creation presents real opportunities for families across the country from construction crews pouring the concrete, to specialised electricians wiring up racks of servers, and the full-time technicians who will keep these digital brains running day and night.In Abilene, the first phase of OpenAI’s development of Stargate data centres is already humming with activity. The first truckloads of Nvidia’s brand-new GB200 chips have arrived, and OpenAI’s researchers are already using them to see what their next AI models are capable of.Of course, a project this huge is never a two-player game. Wh...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 13:08:26 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-and-oracle-announce-stargate-ai-data-centre-deal/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X Data Center Fire in Oregon Started Inside Power Cabinet, Authorities Say</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/x-data-center-fire-in-oregon-started-inside-power-cabinet-authorities-say/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 11:01:20 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/x-data-center-fire-in-oregon-started-inside-power-cabinet-authorities-say/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI’s ChatGPT Agent Is Haunting My Browser</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/browser-haunted-by-ai-agents/</link>
      <description>New tools from OpenAI and Perplexity can browse the web for you. If the idea takes off, these generative AI agents could turn the internet into a ghost town where only bots roam.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/browser-haunted-by-ai-agents/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaked Memo: Anthropic CEO Says the Company Will Pursue Gulf State Investments After All</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/anthropic-dario-amodei-gulf-state-leaked-memo/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:46:32 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/anthropic-dario-amodei-gulf-state-leaked-memo/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI&#x27;s New CEO of Applications Strikes Hyper-Optimistic Tone in First Memo to Staff</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-fidji-simo-note-employees/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 17:05:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-fidji-simo-note-employees/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Apple is playing it slow with AI</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/why-apple-is-playing-it-slow-with-ai/</link>
      <description>Apple is taking its time with AI. While most tech companies are racing to push out AI features as fast as they can, Apple is doing the opposite. Its big announcement – Apple Intelligence – won’t arrive for most users until 2026. That’s a long delay in a market where speed seems to matter more than quality. But maybe that’s the whole point.At this year’s WWDC, Apple showed off new AI features tied to Siri, writing tools, and app suggestions. It called the bundle “Apple Intelligence,” but those tools won’t be widely available any time soon. For now, they’re limited to beta users on select devices in the US. The rest of the world will have to wait. According to Macworld, even early access to Apple Intelligence is expected to be restricted, and many users may not see the features until iOS 18.4 (at the earliest) in 2025. A wider release could slip into 2026.Not falling behind – just not rushing inTo some, the delay looks like Apple falling behind. OpenAI has already rolled out GPT-4o, Google is squeezing Gemini into Android, and Microsoft has pushed Copilot into Office, Windows, and pretty much everything else. Compared to that, Apple seems slow.Apple tends not to ship bad software. It delays when things aren’t working. The company has a long history of waiting until something is polished before pushing it out. That kind of caution can be frustrating, but it also avoids something worse: giving people tools that don’t work properly.Meanwhile, competitors ship bugsPlenty of companies don’t seem to care about quality. Microsoft’s Copilot, for example, often gives wrong answers, makes up citations, or produces junk text. ChatGPT has its own set of problems, from hallucinating facts to giving inconsistent results. Even tools like Claude or Gemini, which show promise in short bursts, tend to fall short on long-term tasks or anything that needs precision.Ask developers what it’s like using AI to write production code, and you’ll often hear the same message: it works fine for code snippets or boilerplate, but it’s more work than help when it comes to complex projects. Fixing AI-written code often takes longer than writing it from scratch.Apple’s delay might be the smarter playAn opinion piece from TechRadar captured the consumer viewpoint. The author said they were gla...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 07:54:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/why-apple-is-playing-it-slow-with-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech giants split on EU AI code as compliance deadline looms</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-ai-code-tech-giants-microsoft-meta-split-compliance/</link>
      <description>The implementation of the EU’s AI General-Purpose Code of Practice has exposed deep divisions among major technology companies. Microsoft has signalled its intention to sign the European Union’s voluntary AI compliance framework while Meta flatly refuses participation, calling the guidelines regulatory overreach that will stifle innovation. Microsoft President Brad Smith told Reuters on Friday, “I […]
The post Tech giants split on EU AI code as compliance deadline looms appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 07:44:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-ai-code-tech-giants-microsoft-meta-split-compliance/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>