<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 09:04:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>The Trump-Intel Deal Is Official</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/trump-announce-intel-deal-equity-stake/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 21:54:53 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/trump-announce-intel-deal-equity-stake/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join Our Next Livestream: Back to School in the Age of AI</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/livestream-back-to-school-in-the-age-of-ai/</link>
      <description>Bring your stories and questions on August 28 as we explore our latest investigations into how tech is shaping education today.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:53:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/livestream-back-to-school-in-the-age-of-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rachel James, AbbVie: Harnessing AI for corporate cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/rachel-james-abbvie-harnessing-ai-for-corporate-cybersecurity/</link>
      <description>Cybersecurity is in the midst of a fresh arms race, and the powerful weapon of choice in this new era is AI.AI offers a classic double-edged sword: a powerful shield for defenders and a potent new tool for those with malicious intent. Navigating this complex battleground requires a steady hand and a deep understanding of both the technology and the people who would abuse it.To get a view from the front lines, AI News caught up with Rachel James, Principal AI ML Threat Intelligence Engineer at global biopharmaceutical company AbbVie.“In addition to the built in AI augmentation that has been vendor-provided in our current tools, we also use LLM analysis on our detections, observations, correlations and associated rules,” James explains.James and her team are using large language models to sift through a mountain of security alerts, looking for patterns, spotting duplicates, and finding dangerous gaps in their defences before an attacker can.“We use this to determine similarity, duplication and provide gap analysis,” she adds, noting that the next step is to weave in even more external threat data. “We are looking to enhance this with the integration of threat intelligence in our next phase.”Central to this operation is a specialised threat intelligence platform called OpenCTI, which helps them build a unified picture of threats from a sea of digital noise.AI is the engine that makes this cybersecurity effort possible, taking vast quantities of jumbled, unstructured text and neatly organising it into a standard format known as STIX. The grand vision, James says, is to use language models to connect this core intelligence with all other areas of their security operation, from vulnerability management to third-party risk.Taking advantage of this power, however, comes with a healthy dose of caution. As a key contributor to a major industry initiative, James is acutely aware of the pitfalls.“I would be remiss if I didn’t mention the work of a wonderful group of folks I am a part of – the ’OWASP Top 10 for GenAI’ as a foundational way of understanding vulnerabilities that GenAI can introduce,” she says.Beyond specific vulnerabilities, James points at three fundamental trade-offs that business leaders must confront:Accepting the risk that comes with the creative but...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 14:48:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/rachel-james-abbvie-harnessing-ai-for-corporate-cybersecurity/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huawei Cloud’s broad, open approach wins it Gartner honours</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/huawei-clouds-open-approach-wins-it-gartner-honours-magic-quadrant-2025-for-container-management/</link>
      <description>The big three cloud providers tend to snap up the majority of hosting honours for containerised workflows. Google, AWS, and Microsoft are the de facto hosting providers, as you might expect, with Red Hat, Alibaba, and SUSE comprising the other household names in the microservices space.But the latest Gartner Magic Quadrant for Container Management 2025 positions Huawei in the Leaders quadrant for the first time. Huawei Cloud is a company that’s quietly making inroads into enterprise mindsets all over the world, and innovating – especially with AI-related workloads – despite the best efforts of the current US government to stymie global competition in the space.Huawei Cloud scored the highest global customer recognition score (4.7) of the companies in Gartner’s paper, beating fellow Chinese behemoths Tencent and Alibaba, plus the ‘big three’ of AWS, Google GCP and Microsoft Azure.According to Gartner, Huawei Cloud offers the most complete container product matrix in the cloud industry, where its platforms can be found in public, distributed, and hybrid clouds, and edge environments.The company’s big wins in terms of clients and users get little coverage in the US and Europe, but it’s proving an effective provider for companies like media service Starzplay (which streamed the 2024 Cricket World Cup across the Middle East and Central Asia) and logistics giant Ninja Van in Singapore.South America and Africa, too, have been the scene of several successes for the Chinese company, notably Nigeria’s e-commerce platform Konga, which uses a cloud native architecture based on Huawei Cloud’s CCT Turbo, and major power utility Chilquina Energia in Chile. The latter organisation speaks of a 90% average performance improvement across its stack.The Linux Foundation’s CNCF (cloud-native computing foundation) steers an open and interoperable approach to all elements of cloud computing, and Huawei is the only Chinese cloud provider with a vice-chair position on the organisation’s Technical Oversight Committee. The company also maintains more than 20 project maintainer seats at the CNCF. It’s also an active donor to projects under the CNCF’s oversight, including KubeEdge, Karmada, and Kuasar.Huawei’s offerings include container products like CCE Turbo, CCE Autopilot, the distr...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 14:21:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/huawei-clouds-open-approach-wins-it-gartner-honours-magic-quadrant-2025-for-container-management/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proton’s privacy-first Lumo AI assistant gets a major upgrade</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/proton-privacy-lumo-ai-assistant-major-upgrade/</link>
      <description>The privacy defenders at Proton have deployed an upgrade to their AI assistant, Lumo, that promises faster and more intelligent responses.AI assistants can be incredibly useful for drafting emails, planning a trip, or just satisfying a random curiosity, but there’s always that nagging feeling that every question you ask, every idea you explore, is being logged, analysed, and fed back into a massive corporate machine. You’re constantly trading a bit of your privacy for a bit of convenience.Lumo is now a whole lot smarter. Proton is calling it version 1.1, and the main takeaway is the AI assistant is better at pretty much everything. It’s faster, it gives more detailed answers, and it’s much more up-to-date on what’s happening in the world.For specific metrics, Proton is claiming a 200% improvement in Lumo’s ability to ‘reason’ through complex problems—you know, the tricky multi-step stuff where other AIs tend to get lost. On top of that, Proton says their AI assistant is now 170% better at actually understanding the context of what you’re asking, and for the coders out there, it’s seen a 40% boost in generating correct code.But here’s the part that really matters: it does all of this without snooping on you.Unlike the big players, Proton’s entire approach to AI is built around privacy. When you chat with most AIs, you’re essentially having a conversation in a room full of people taking notes. With Lumo, you’re in a locked room, and only you have the key. Your conversations are encrypted in such a way that nobody at Proton can ever read them. They don’t save your chats, and they don’t use your personal conversations to train their AI.To prove their privacy claims, Proton has made the code for their AI assistant’s mobile apps open-source. That means Proton is letting anyone look under the bonnet to check that Lumo’s engine is running the way they claim it is. It’s about building trust, not just demanding it.So, what’s the catch? Well, to get the absolute best performance and unlimited use, you’re encouraged to sign up for Lumo Plus. And that, right there, is the point. Proton is betting that some of us would rather pay a few quid for a service that respects our privacy than get a “free” service where our data is the real price of admission.This latest update t...</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:48:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/proton-privacy-lumo-ai-assistant-major-upgrade/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI servers are transforming Taiwan’s electronics manufacturing giants</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-servers-transform-taiwan-manufacturing-giants/</link>
      <description>The revenue charts tell a story that would have seemed impossible just three years ago: AI servers are now generating more money than iPhones for Taiwan’s manufacturing giants. For the first time in decades, Taiwan’s manufacturing titans are watching their bread-and-butter consumer electronics businesses get overtaken by artificial intelligence infrastructure – a shift that’s rewriting […]
The post How AI servers are transforming Taiwan’s electronics manufacturing giants appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:40:45 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-servers-transform-taiwan-manufacturing-giants/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet Wukong, the AI Chatbot China Has Installed on Its Space Station</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/meet-wukong-chinas-first-ai-chatbot-on-a-space-station/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 11:33:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/meet-wukong-chinas-first-ai-chatbot-on-a-space-station/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Did a $10 Billion Startup Let Me Vibe-Code for Them—and Why Did I Love It?</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/why-did-a-10-billion-dollar-startup-let-me-vibe-code-for-them-and-why-did-i-love-it/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/why-did-a-10-billion-dollar-startup-let-me-vibe-code-for-them-and-why-did-i-love-it/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gen AI makes no financial difference in 95% of cases</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/gen-ai-makes-no-financial-difference-in-95-of-cases/</link>
      <description>Stocks in US AI technology companies fell in value at the close of trading yesterday, with the NASDAQ Composite index down 1.4%. Among those losing value were Palantir, down 9.4% and Arm Holdings down 5%. According to the Financial Times [paywall], Tuesday saw the biggest one-day fall in the market since the beginning of August. […]
The post Gen AI makes no financial difference in 95% of cases appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 18:57:06 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/gen-ai-makes-no-financial-difference-in-95-of-cases/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Large Language Models Dream of AI Agents?</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/sleeptime-compute-chatbots-memory/</link>
      <description>For AI models, knowing what to remember might be as important as knowing what to forget. Welcome to the era of “sleeptime compute.”</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/sleeptime-compute-chatbots-memory/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fitbit App Is Turning Into an AI-Powered Personal Health Coach</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/fitbit-app-ai-personal-health-coach/</link>
      <description>Built with Gemini, Google’s AI health coach will be everything but a doctor.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:42:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/fitbit-app-ai-personal-health-coach/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Pixel 10 Series, Pixel Watch 4, Pixel Buds 2a: Specs, Features, Release Date</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/google-pixel-10-series-pixel-watch-4-pixel-buds-2a/</link>
      <description>The Pixel 10 series is here. These are the first official flagship Android phones with magnetic Qi2 wireless charging. Also in tow are the Pixel Watch 4 and Pixel Buds 2a earbuds.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/google-pixel-10-series-pixel-watch-4-pixel-buds-2a/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Crazy Features Powering Google&#x27;s Pixel 10 Phones (and Watch)</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/all-the-new-ai-features-in-google-pixel-10-phones/</link>
      <description>Google’s latest AI features include real-time translated phone calls in your own AI-generated voice, an AI camera coach that makes you a better Instagram husband, and a voicemail replacement.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/all-the-new-ai-features-in-google-pixel-10-phones/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Cloud unveils AI ally for security teams</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-cloud-unveils-ai-ally-for-security-teams/</link>
      <description>Google Cloud believes the answer to overworked security teams isn’t just more tools, but an AI-powered ally.At its Security Summit 2025, Google laid out its vision for a future where AI frees up human security experts from tedious work to focus on what matters most.The central idea is to use AI to defend your organisation while securing your own AI initiatives from attack. As businesses increasingly rely on AI agents, these agents themselves become a new frontier for security concerns.Securing the AI ecosystemBefore AI can become a trusted defender, its own environment must be secure. To this end, Google Cloud is enhancing its AI Protection solution within the Security Command Center.New capabilities, arriving soon in preview, will automatically discover all the AI agents and servers in your environment. This will give security teams a clear view of their entire AI agent ecosystem, helping them to spot vulnerabilities, misconfigurations, and risky interactions.Real-time protection is also getting a boost. Model Armor’s in-line protection is being extended to prompts and responses within Agentspace, helping to block threats like prompt injection and data leaks as they happen.To ensure AI agents are always playing by the rules, new posture controls will help them stick to company security policies. And with new threat detections powered by intelligence from Mandiant and Google Cloud, security teams can now better spot and respond to unusual or suspicious behaviour from their AI assets.Rise of the agentic SOCPerhaps the most forward-looking announcement is Google’s vision for an “agentic security operations centre (SOC)”. Imagine a system where AI agents collaborate to manage threats, automate alert investigations, and even help engineers create new detections to fill security gaps.The first step in this direction is the new Alert Investigation agent, which is now in preview. This tool acts like a junior analyst, autonomously looking into security events, analysing command-line activity, and mapping out process trees based on the proven methods of Mandiant’s frontline experts. The agent provides its verdict on alerts and suggests next steps for human analysts, promising to cut down on manual work and speed up response times.AI security built on Google Cloud’s ...</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 15:21:44 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-cloud-unveils-ai-ally-for-security-teams/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yext Unveils Scout and Launches Webinar to Help Brands Stay Visible in AI &amp; Local Search</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/yext-unveils-scout-and-launches-webinar-to-help-brands-stay-visible-in-ai-local-search/</link>
      <description>In March Yext, the leading brand visibility platform, launched Yext Scout, an AI search and competitive intelligence agent designed to give brands visibility and actionable insights across both traditional and AI-driven search platforms.Integrated within the Yext platform, Scout provides insights into visibility across traditional and AI search platforms, benchmarks performance against competitors, and delivers actionable recommendations.Yext is set to explore the impact of AI on search behaviour and how Scout can empower brands and marketing professionals across EMEA at the webinar, Winning Search in EMEA: How Yext Scout Drives Visibility Across Local and AI Platforms, on Wednesday, 24 September 2025 at 1PM BST / 2PM CEST.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 12:12:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/yext-unveils-scout-and-launches-webinar-to-help-brands-stay-visible-in-ai-local-search/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese ‘Virtual Human’ Salespeople Are Outperforming Their Real Human Counterparts</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/artificial-intelligence-tiktok-shop-ecommerce-china/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/artificial-intelligence-tiktok-shop-ecommerce-china/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Saw the Future of AI Film and It Was Empty</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/cream-of-the-slop-an-ai-film-festival-screening-left-me-with-more-questions-than-answers/</link>
      <description>From a POV butterfly larvae doc to something that resembled a perfume commercial, Runway AI’s film festival selections did little to convince me of AI’s artistry.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/cream-of-the-slop-an-ai-film-festival-screening-left-me-with-more-questions-than-answers/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Nvidia Blackwell chip for China may outpace H20 model</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-nvidia-blackwell-chip-for-china-may-outpace-h20-model/</link>
      <description>Nvidia is working on a new AI chip for China that could be stronger than the H20 model it currently sells there, according to people familiar with the plans, Reuters reported. The chip will be based on the company’s latest Blackwell design.Last week, US President Donald Trump suggested that more advanced Nvidia chips might eventually be sold in China. But approval is uncertain, as US officials remain wary of giving Beijing too much access to American AI technology.The new chip, referred to internally as the B30A, is expected to use a single-die design. That means all the core parts of the chip are built on one piece of silicon, instead of split in two dies like in Nvidia’s flagship B300. People familiar with the details said this would likely give the B30A about half the power of the B300, but still make it stronger than the H20.Like the H20, the B30A will feature high-bandwidth memory and NVLink, Nvidia’s technology for moving data quickly between processors. Final specifications haven’t been locked in, but the company hopes to send samples to Chinese customers for testing as early as next month.Nvidia, in a statement about its strategy for China, said: “We evaluate a variety of products for our roadmap, so that we can be prepared to compete to the extent that governments allow. Everything we offer is with the full approval of the applicable authorities and designed solely for beneficial commercial use.”US Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick told CNBC that Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang has been pushing for approval. “Of course he would like to sell a new chip to China,” Lutnick said, adding that Huang often pitches the idea directly to the president. “The president listens to our great technology companies, and he’ll decide how he wants to play it. But the fact Jensen is pitching a new chip shouldn’t surprise anybody.”US-China trade tensions grow over Nvidia chipsThe question of how much access China should have to advanced AI chips has become one of the main points of tension between Washington and Beijing. China accounted for 13% of Nvidia’s revenue last year.Nvidia only resumed selling the H20 in July after US regulators abruptly halted sales in April. The H20 was designed in 2023 to meet export rules which restricted chip sales to China.Donald Trump said recen...</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 08:44:32 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-nvidia-blackwell-chip-for-china-may-outpace-h20-model/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK urged to seize ‘once-in-20-years’ AI chip design opportunity</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uk-urged-seize-once-20-years-ai-chip-design-opportunity/</link>
      <description>The Council for Science and Technology (CST) urges the UK to seize a “once-in-20-years opportunity” to build a world-class AI chip design industry, or risk becoming a nation that simply consumes, rather than creates, the technology that will define our future. In a report published this week, the council argues the UK must get serious […]
The post UK urged to seize ‘once-in-20-years’ AI chip design opportunity appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 12:27:29 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uk-urged-seize-once-20-years-ai-chip-design-opportunity/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hidden costs of AI implementation every CEO should know</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/hidden-costs-of-ai-implementation-every-ceo-should-know/</link>
      <description>AI has been a game-changer for many businesses, and CEOs are eager to get in on the action. Smart move! But, before you start envisioning robots handling your customer service and algorithms optimising everything from inventory to cafeteria orders, let’s talk about the elephant in the room: the costs no one mentions at those slick AI vendor presentations.Naturally, everyone knows that AI involves up-front investment. What they don’t tell you is that the sticker price is just the tip of the iceberg. The real costs lurk beneath the waterline, waiting to ambush even the most experienced executives.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 10:32:15 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/hidden-costs-of-ai-implementation-every-ceo-should-know/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why security chiefs demand urgent regulation of AI like DeepSeek</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/why-security-chiefs-demand-urgent-regulation-of-ai-like-deepseek/</link>
      <description>Anxiety is growing among Chief Information Security Officers (CISOs) in security operation centres, particularly around Chinese AI giant DeepSeek.AI was heralded as a new dawn for business efficiency and innovation, but for the people on the front lines of corporate defence, it’s casting some very long and dark shadows.Four in five (81%) UK CISOs believe the Chinese AI chatbot requires urgent regulation from the government. They fear that without swift intervention, the tool could become the catalyst for a full-scale national cyber crisis. This isn’t speculative unease; it’s a direct response to a technology whose data handling practices and potential for misuse are raising alarm bells at the highest levels of enterprise security.The findings, commissioned by Absolute Security for its UK Resilience Risk Index Report, are based on a poll of 250 CISOs at large UK organisations. The data suggests that the theoretical threat of AI has now landed firmly on the CISO’s desk, and their reactions have been decisive.In what would have been almost unthinkable a couple of years ago, over a third (34%) of these security leaders have already implemented outright bans on AI tools due to cybersecurity concerns. A similar number, 30 percent, have already pulled the plug on specific AI deployments within their organisations.This retreat is not a sign of Luddism but a pragmatic response to an escalating problem. Businesses are already facing complex and hostile threats, as evidenced by high-profile incidents like the recent Harrods breach. CISOs are struggling to keep pace, and the addition of sophisticated AI tools into the attacker’s arsenal is a challenge many feel ill-equipped to handle.A growing security readiness gap for AI platforms like DeepSeekThe core of the issue with platforms like DeepSeek lies in their potential to expose sensitive corporate data and be weaponised by cybercriminals.Three out of five (60%) CISOs predict a direct increase in cyberattacks as a result of DeepSeek’s proliferation. An identical proportion reports that the technology is already tangling their privacy and governance frameworks, making an already difficult job almost impossible.This has prompted a shift in perspective. Once viewed as a potential silver bullet for cybersecurity, AI is now...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 15:13:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/why-security-chiefs-demand-urgent-regulation-of-ai-like-deepseek/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Perplexity AI’s $34.5b Chrome bid a strategic master stroke or elaborate PR stunt?</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/perplexity-ai-chrome-bid-analysis/</link>
      <description>The artificial intelligence company Perplexity’s audacious offer to acquire Chrome has sent shockwaves through Silicon Valley, but questions remain about whether the move represents a genuine strategy or a calculated publicity stunt. Perplexity AI made an unsolicited $34.5 billion bid for Google’s Chrome browser last Tuesday, a figure that exceeds the startup’s own $18 billion […]
The post Is Perplexity AI’s $34.5b Chrome bid a strategic master stroke or elaborate PR stunt? appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 14:49:09 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/perplexity-ai-chrome-bid-analysis/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>