<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 09:04:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Join Our Livestream: Inside the AI Copyright Battles</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/livestream-ai-copyright-battles/</link>
      <description>Curious about generative AI and copyright? Subscribers can join WIRED live on July 16 as we answer your questions about this critical topic.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 17:40:06 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/livestream-ai-copyright-battles/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI is rewriting the rules of the insurance industry</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-is-rewriting-the-rules-of-insurance-industry/</link>
      <description>Despite its traditionally risk-averse nature, the insurance industry is being fundamentally reshaped by AI. AI has already become vital for the insurance industry, touching everything from complex risk calculations to the way insurers talk to their customers. However, while nearly eight out of ten companies are dipping their toes in the AI water, a similar […]
The post AI is rewriting the rules of the insurance industry appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 15:12:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-is-rewriting-the-rules-of-insurance-industry/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft and OpenAI&#x27;s AGI Fight Is Bigger Than a Contract</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/microsoft-and-openais-agi-fight-is-bigger-than-a-contract/</link>
      <description>A key clause in Microsoft and OpenAI&#x27;s deal embodies the raging divide between AGI true believers and those who think it&#x27;s still a long ways off.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 12:11:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/microsoft-and-openais-agi-fight-is-bigger-than-a-contract/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM Power11 targets enterprise AI adoption with zero-downtime architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ibm-power11-enterprise-servers-zero-downtime-ai/</link>
      <description>IBM’s Power11 enterprise servers address a persistent challenge in enterprise computing: how to deploy AI workloads without compromising the rock-solid reliability that mission-critical applications demand. Announced on July 8, 2025, the Power11 reflects IBM’s bet that enterprises will prioritise integrated solutions over the current patchwork of specialised AI hardware and traditional servers that many organisations currently manage.Understanding the core innovationPower11 enterprise servers are designed around the premise that businesses cannot afford downtime. The system promises “99.9999% uptime” – a figure that translates to less than 32 seconds of unplanned downtime per year.This represents what IBM calls “the most resilient server in the history of the IBM Power platform.” For non-technical readers, this level of reliability means that critical business applications – from banking transactions to healthcare records – can operate continuously without interruption.The zero-planned downtime feature allows system maintenance, updates, and patches while applications continue running, eliminating the traditional maintenance windows that typically require taking systems offline.AI integration made practicalThe servers include on-chip acceleration for AI inference – the process of using trained AI models to make predictions or decisions in real-time business scenarios.The system will support IBM’s upcoming Spyre Accelerator, a specialised chip designed for AI-intensive workloads, expected in Q4 2025. The combination should allow organisations to run AI applications alongside traditional workloads without requiring separate infrastructure investments.Performance and efficiency gainsThe technical specifications show improvement over previous generations, with up to 55% better core performance compared to Power9 systems and up to 45% more capacity than Power10 systems, according to the company’s own metrics, with the ensuing energy efficiency representing another benefit.The servers deliver twice the performance per watt compared to comparable x86 servers and up to 28% better server efficiency when using the new Energy Efficient Mode versus Maximum Performance Mode.Security and cyber resilienceThe integrated IBM Power Cyber Vault solution addresses growing cybe...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 09:18:44 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ibm-power11-enterprise-servers-zero-downtime-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Video Games Became the New Battleground for Actors and AI Protections</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/video-games-voice-actors-strike-over-artificial-intelligence/</link>
      <description>Voice actors ended their 11-month strike against the video game industry, but their fight against AI is just beginning.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 17:13:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/video-games-voice-actors-strike-over-artificial-intelligence/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Asked, We Answered: All of Your AI Angst</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-you-asked-we-answered-all-of-your-ai-angst/</link>
      <description>Welcome to Uncanny Valley&#x27;s very first Q&amp;A, where our host addresses your burning AI-related questions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 16:27:53 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-you-asked-we-answered-all-of-your-ai-angst/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google’s open MedGemma AI models could transform healthcare</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-open-medgemma-ai-models-healthcare/</link>
      <description>Instead of keeping their new MedGemma AI models locked behind expensive APIs, Google will hand these powerful tools to healthcare developers.The new arrivals are called MedGemma 27B Multimodal and MedSigLIP and they’re part of Google’s growing collection of open-source healthcare AI models. What makes these special isn’t just their technical prowess, but the fact that hospitals, researchers, and developers can download them, modify them, and run them however they see fit.Google’s AI meets real healthcareThe flagship MedGemma 27B model doesn’t just read medical text like previous versions did; it can actually “look” at medical images and understand what it’s seeing. Whether it’s chest X-rays, pathology slides, or patient records potentially spanning months or years, it can process all of this information together, much like a doctor would.The performance figures are quite impressive. When tested on MedQA, a standard medical knowledge benchmark, the 27B text model scored 87.7%. That puts it within spitting distance of much larger, more expensive models whilst costing about a tenth as much to run. For cash-strapped healthcare systems, that’s potentially transformative.The smaller sibling, MedGemma 4B, might be more modest in size but it’s no slouch. Despite being tiny by modern AI standards, it scored 64.4% on the same tests, making it one of the best performers in its weight class. More importantly, when US board-certified radiologists reviewed chest X-ray reports it had written, they deemed 81% accurate enough to guide actual patient care.MedSigLIP: A featherweight powerhouseAlongside these generative AI models, Google has released MedSigLIP. At just 400 million parameters, it’s practically featherweight compared to today’s AI giants, but it’s been specifically trained to understand medical images in ways that general-purpose models cannot.This little powerhouse has been fed a diet of chest X-rays, tissue samples, skin condition photos, and eye scans. The result? It can spot patterns and features that matter in medical contexts whilst still handling everyday images perfectly well.MedSigLIP creates a bridge between images and text. Show it a chest X-ray, and ask it to find similar cases in a database, and it’ll understand not just visual similarities but medi...</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:17:31 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-open-medgemma-ai-models-healthcare/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Is a Lousy Chef</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/dishgen-ai-recipes-tested/</link>
      <description>I asked an AI-powered recipe generator to make some menus. It didn’t tell me to put glue in my guacamole, but the results didn’t come close to besting recipes written by professionals.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/dishgen-ai-recipes-tested/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr. ChatGPT Will See You Now</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/dr-chatgpt-will-see-you-now-artificial-intelligence-llms-openai-health-diagnoses/</link>
      <description>Patients and doctors are turning to AI for diagnoses and treatment recommendations, often with stellar results, but problems arise when experts and algorithms disagree.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 10:46:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/dr-chatgpt-will-see-you-now-artificial-intelligence-llms-openai-health-diagnoses/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk Unveils Grok 4 Amid Controversy Over Chatbot’s Antisemitic Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/grok-4-elon-musk-xai-antisemitic-posts/</link>
      <description>In a livestream with xAI colleagues, the billionaire entrepreneur described current AI systems as “primitive” and not for “serious” commercial use.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 06:34:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/grok-4-elon-musk-xai-antisemitic-posts/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>McDonald’s AI Hiring Bot Exposed Millions of Applicants&#x27; Data to Hackers Using the Password ‘123456’</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/mcdonalds-ai-hiring-chat-bot-paradoxai/</link>
      <description>Basic security flaws left the personal info of tens of millions of McDonald’s job-seekers vulnerable on the “McHire” site built by AI software firm Paradox.ai.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 19:28:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/mcdonalds-ai-hiring-chat-bot-paradoxai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Kind of AI Model Lets Data Owners Take Control</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/flexolmo-ai-model-lets-data-owners-take-control/</link>
      <description>A novel approach from the Allen Institute for AI enables data to be removed from an artificial intelligence model even after it has already been used for training.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 17:59:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/flexolmo-ai-model-lets-data-owners-take-control/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tencent improves testing creative AI models with new benchmark</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tencent-improves-testing-creative-ai-models-new-benchmark/</link>
      <description>Tencent has introduced a new benchmark, ArtifactsBench, that aims to fix current problems with testing creative AI models. Ever asked an AI to build something like a simple webpage or a chart and received something that works but has a poor user experience? The buttons might be in the wrong place, the colours might clash, […]
The post Tencent improves testing creative AI models with new benchmark appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 14:10:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tencent-improves-testing-creative-ai-models-new-benchmark/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grok Is Spewing Antisemitic Garbage on X</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/grok-antisemitic-posts-x-xai/</link>
      <description>Elon Musk’s chatbot has gone on a tirade, praising Adolf Hitler and parroting antisemitic tropes.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 23:32:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/grok-antisemitic-posts-x-xai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple loses key AI leader to Meta</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/apple-loses-key-ai-leader-to-meta/</link>
      <description>Apple is nursing a fresh wound this week after losing one of its most crucial AI leaders to Meta. Ruoming Pang, the executive who oversaw Apple Intelligence, has jumped ship to join Meta’s new Superintelligence Labs.Pang wasn’t just any Apple employee. He led a 100-strong army of engineers crafting the language models that make your iPhone summarise texts, generate those Genmoji, and prioritise your notifications. Now he’s traded the Apple Park spaceship for Meta’s Menlo Park headquarters, becoming the latest big name to answer Mark Zuckerberg’s call.The leading exec’s departure is a gut punch to a company that’s been scrambling to prove it can play in the AI big leagues. The timing couldn’t be worse, either.Just last month, Pang’s right-hand man, Tom Gunter, had already packed his bags and left. Pang’s departure was reported by Bloomberg and the outlet’s sources suggest Apple is losing the talent it desperately needs.Apple spent years building up its AI chops, focusing on that privacy-first approach that’s supposed to be its secret sauce. However, many believe that focus has led to the company falling behind in AI with many Apple Intelligence features yet to roll out. The haemorrhaging of talent isn’t going to help with efforts to catch up.Meta’s cheque book diplomacy for AI talentMeanwhile, Meta’s playing the talent acquisition game like a Premier League club during transfer season. Word on the street is that they’re throwing around signing bonuses that would even make a footballer blush, and frankly, it’s working.Since last April, there’ve been whispers about Meta’s shopping spree through Silicon Valley’s AI departments. Apple hasn’t been the sole target, with talent at OpenAI and Google also receiving tempting offers as top companies fight to recruit (and retain) expertise.It’s not subtle, and it’s certainly not cheap. Critics are calling it market manipulation, but you can’t argue with the results. Meta’s managed to hoover up some of the brightest minds in AI, all in service of their grand vision for artificial general intelligence.The creation of Superintelligence Labs isn’t just corporate restructuring—it’s a declaration of war. Meta’s essentially saying they’re going toe-to-toe with OpenAI and Google’s DeepMind, and they’re backing it up with seriou...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 14:37:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/apple-loses-key-ai-leader-to-meta/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tencent Hunyuan3D-PolyGen: A model for ‘art-grade’ 3D assets</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tencent-hunyuan3d-polygen-a-model-for-art-grade-3d-assets/</link>
      <description>Tencent has released a model that could be quite literally game-changing for how developers create 3D assets. The new Hunyuan3D-PolyGen model is Tencent’s first attempt at delivering what they’re calling “art-grade” 3D generation, specifically built for the professionals who craft the digital worlds we play in. Creating high-quality 3D assets has always been a bottleneck […]
The post Tencent Hunyuan3D-PolyGen: A model for ‘art-grade’ 3D assets appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 14:55:38 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tencent-hunyuan3d-polygen-a-model-for-art-grade-3d-assets/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>