<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 09:04:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>YouTube Thinks AI Is Its Next Big Bang</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/youtube-thinks-ai-is-its-next-big-bang/</link>
      <description>On its 20th anniversary, YouTube is venturing into an era of AI-generated video, and may never be the same.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/youtube-thinks-ai-is-its-next-big-bang/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TechEx Europe 2025: Practical learnings for AI leaders</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/techex-europe-2025-practical-learnings-for-ai-leaders/</link>
      <description>On 24–25 September 2025, the RAI in Amsterdam will host TechEx Europe, an event that brings together 8,000+ participants and 250+ speakers in five co-located events: AI &amp; Big Data Expo, Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo, IoT Tech Expo, Digital Transformation Week, and Data Centre Expo. The event offers opportunities to engage with peer executives […]
The post TechEx Europe 2025: Practical learnings for AI leaders appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:15:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/techex-europe-2025-practical-learnings-for-ai-leaders/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta Accused of Torrenting Porn to Advance Its Goal of AI ‘Superintelligence’</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/meta-lawsuit-strike-3-porn-copyright-ai/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/meta-lawsuit-strike-3-porn-copyright-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christian Spindeldreher, Dell Technologies: Powering AI at scale</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/christian-spindeldreher-dell-technologies-powering-ai-at-scale/</link>
      <description>Dell Technologies is betting on AI as companies move from small pilots to full-scale deployments, with the focus now on how organisations can turn AI into measurable results. But scaling AI is not easy. It demands strong infrastructure, reliable data management, and the ability to deploy models quickly in different workflows. Dell has positioned itself […]
The post Christian Spindeldreher, Dell Technologies: Powering AI at scale appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 08:24:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/christian-spindeldreher-dell-technologies-powering-ai-at-scale/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump jokes about AI while US and UK sign new tech deal</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/trump-jokes-about-ai-while-us-and-uk-sign-new-tech-deal/</link>
      <description>US President Donald Trump said on Thursday that AI was “taking over the world,” and joked that he hoped tech executives understood it better than he did. The comment came as Trump and UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer hosted a gathering of business and technology leaders in London during the president’s second state visit to […]
The post Trump jokes about AI while US and UK sign new tech deal appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 08:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/trump-jokes-about-ai-while-us-and-uk-sign-new-tech-deal/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Move Aside, Chatbots: AI Humanoids Are Here</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-move-aside-chatbots-ai-humanoids-are-here/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:45:20 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-move-aside-chatbots-ai-humanoids-are-here/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jensen Huang Wants You to Know He’s Getting a Lot Out of the ‘Fantastic’ Nvidia-Intel Deal</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/nvidia-intel-announce-collaboration-chips/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:44:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/nvidia-intel-announce-collaboration-chips/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huawei announces new Ascend chips, to power world’s most powerful clusters</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/huawei-announces-new-ascend-chips-to-power-worlds-most-powerful-clusters/</link>
      <description>Chinese technology giant Huawei announced its plans for the next generations of its Ascend chip line at the Huawei Connect 2025 event in Shanghai this week. In his keynote to the conference, deputy chair of the Huawei board, Eric Xu, said that 2025 had been a “memorable year,” and noted the debut of DeepSeek-R1 in […]
The post Huawei announces new Ascend chips, to power world’s most powerful clusters appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:50:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/huawei-announces-new-ascend-chips-to-power-worlds-most-powerful-clusters/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China Turns Legacy Chips Into a Trade Weapon</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/china-probe-us-chip-makers-tiktok-deal/</link>
      <description>As Washington pushes for a TikTok deal, Beijing is countering with probes into American chipmakers.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/china-probe-us-chip-makers-tiktok-deal/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Psychosis Is Rarely Psychosis at All</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/ai-psychosis-is-rarely-psychosis-at-all/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/ai-psychosis-is-rarely-psychosis-at-all/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang Is Bananas for Google Gemini’s AI Image Generator</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/jensen-huang-has-gone-nano-bananas/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 13:53:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/jensen-huang-has-gone-nano-bananas/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-enabled threats and stricter regulation in France</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-enabled-threats-and-stricter-regulation-in-france/</link>
      <description>A new research report from technology advisory firm Information Services Group (ISG) has revealed AI threats and more stringent regulations are shifting the French cybersecurity landscape, resulting in businesses reassessing their security strategies. Increasing security budgets mean many French enterprises require fresh guidance and expertise to establish effective priorities and combat their security challenges. According […]
The post AI-enabled threats and stricter regulation in France appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 11:58:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-enabled-threats-and-stricter-regulation-in-france/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSI and HuLoop deliver AI-driven efficiency to banks</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/csi-and-huloop-deliver-ai-driven-efficiency-to-banks/</link>
      <description>Fintech, regtech, and cybersecurity vendor, CSI has teamed with HuLoop, a provider of an AI-powered, no-code automation platform, to help banks improve efficiency. The partnership will present CSI’s NuPoint Core Banking System to financial institutions, and is designed to help companies manage accounts, transactions, and other banking operations. NuPoint customers will have access to HuLoop’s […]
The post CSI and HuLoop deliver AI-driven efficiency to banks appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 08:49:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/csi-and-huloop-deliver-ai-driven-efficiency-to-banks/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Tech Giants Race to Spend Billions in UK AI Push</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/microsoft-nvidia-uk-investment-trump/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 21:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/microsoft-nvidia-uk-investment-trump/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI&#x27;s Teen Safety Features Will Walk a Thin Line</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-launches-teen-safety-features/</link>
      <description>CEO Sam Altman announced an age-prediction system and new parental controls in a blog post on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 20:53:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-launches-teen-safety-features/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew Prince Wants AI Companies to Pay for Their Sins</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/big-interview-podcast-matthew-prince-cloudflare/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/big-interview-podcast-matthew-prince-cloudflare/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mythos AI and lomarlabs deploy sea-pilot AI assistance</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/apas-radar-sea-trial-tests-ai-ocean-transport/</link>
      <description>American maritime technology company Mythos AI has completed the installation of its Advanced Pilot Assistance System (APAS) aboard the vessel CB Pacific, a chemical cargo ship owned by CB Tankers. The APAS project is designed to manage navigation at sea. Unlike most traditional systems in this space that depend largely on machine vision, APAS uses […]
The post Mythos AI and lomarlabs deploy sea-pilot AI assistance appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:05:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/apas-radar-sea-trial-tests-ai-ocean-transport/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>