<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 09:04:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>How background AI builds operational resilience &amp; visible ROI</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-background-ai-builds-operational-resilience-visible-roi/</link>
      <description>If you asked most enterprise leaders which AI tools are delivering ROI, many would point to front-end chatbots or customer support automation. That’s the wrong door. The most value-generating AI systems today aren’t loud, customer-facing marvels. They’re tucked away in backend operations. They work silently, flagging irregularities in real-time, automating risk reviews, mapping data lineage, or helping compliance teams detect anomalies before regulators do. The tools don’t ask for credit, but are saving millions.Operational resilience no longer comes from having the loudest AI tool. It comes from having the smartest one, placed where it quietly does the work of five teams before lunch.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:51:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-background-ai-builds-operational-resilience-visible-roi/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems Can Trick AI Into Helping You Make a Nuclear Weapon</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/poems-can-trick-ai-into-helping-you-make-a-nuclear-weapon/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/poems-can-trick-ai-into-helping-you-make-a-nuclear-weapon/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP outlines new approach to European AI and cloud sovereignty</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/sap-outlines-new-approach-to-european-ai-and-cloud-sovereignty/</link>
      <description>SAP is moving its sovereignty plans forward with EU AI Cloud, a setup meant to unify its efforts in the region under one approach. The goal is to give organisations in Europe more choice and control of how they run AI and cloud services. EU AI Cloud is built to support organisations using SAP’s data […]
The post SAP outlines new approach to European AI and cloud sovereignty appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/sap-outlines-new-approach-to-european-ai-and-cloud-sovereignty/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the MCP spec update boosts security as infrastructure scales</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-the-mcp-spec-update-boosts-security-as-infrastructure-scales/</link>
      <description>The latest MCP spec update fortifies enterprise infrastructure with tighter security, moving AI agents from pilot to production. Marking its first year, the Anthropic-created open-source project released a revised spec this week aimed at the operational headaches keeping generative AI agents stuck in pilot mode. Backed by Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft, and Google Cloud, […]
The post How the MCP spec update boosts security as infrastructure scales appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 13:34:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-the-mcp-spec-update-boosts-security-as-infrastructure-scales/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edge AI inside the human body: Cochlear’s machine learning implant breakthrough</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/edge-ai-medical-devices-cochlear-implants/</link>
      <description>The next frontier for edge AI medical devices isn’t wearables or bedside monitors—it’s inside the human body itself. Cochlear’s newly launched Nucleus Nexa System represents the first cochlear implant capable of running machine learning algorithms while managing extreme power constraints, storing personalised data on-device, and receiving over-the-air firmware updates to improve its AI models over time. For AI […]
The post Edge AI inside the human body: Cochlear’s machine learning implant breakthrough appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/edge-ai-medical-devices-cochlear-implants/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jeff Bezos’ New AI Venture Quietly Acquired an Agentic Computing Startup</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/jeff-bezos-new-ai-company-acquired-agentic-computing-startup/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 20:02:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/jeff-bezos-new-ai-company-acquired-agentic-computing-startup/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Workers Issue Warning About Company’s ‘All-Costs-Justified’ Approach to AI Development</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/amazon-employees-open-letter-artificial-intelligence-layoffs/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:04:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/amazon-employees-open-letter-artificial-intelligence-layoffs/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Trump Administration’s Data Center Push Could Open the Door for New Forever Chemicals</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-trump-administrations-data-center-push-could-open-the-door-for-new-forever-chemicals/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/the-trump-administrations-data-center-push-could-open-the-door-for-new-forever-chemicals/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Microsoft cloud updates support Indonesia’s long-term AI goals</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-microsoft-cloud-updates-support-indonesia-long-term-ai-goals/</link>
      <description>Indonesia’s push into AI-led growth is gaining momentum as more local organisations look for ways to build their own applications, update their systems, and strengthen data oversight. The country now has broader access to cloud and AI tools after Microsoft expanded the services available in the Indonesia Central cloud region, which first went live six […]
The post New Microsoft cloud updates support Indonesia’s long-term AI goals appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-microsoft-cloud-updates-support-indonesia-long-term-ai-goals/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WIRED Roundup: Gemini 3 Release, Nvidia Earnings, Epstein Files Fallout</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-wired-roundup-gemini-3-release-nvidia-earnings-epstein-files-fallout/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 21:24:53 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-wired-roundup-gemini-3-release-nvidia-earnings-epstein-files-fallout/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manufacturing’s pivot: AI as a strategic driver</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manufacturings-pivot-ai-as-a-strategic-driver/</link>
      <description>Manufacturers today are working against rising input costs, labour shortages, supply-chain fragility, and pressure to offer more customised products. AI is becoming an important part of a response to those pressures. When enterprise strategy depends on AI Most manufacturers seek to reduce cost while improving throughput and quality. AI supports these aims by predicting equipment […]
The post Manufacturing’s pivot: AI as a strategic driver appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:04:39 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manufacturings-pivot-ai-as-a-strategic-driver/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adversarial learning breakthrough enables real-time AI security</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/adversarial-learning-breakthrough-real-time-ai-security/</link>
      <description>The ability to execute adversarial learning for real-time AI security offers a decisive advantage over static defence mechanisms. The emergence of AI-driven attacks – utilising reinforcement learning (RL) and Large Language Model (LLM) capabilities – has created a class of “vibe hacking” and adaptive threats that mutate faster than human teams can respond. This represents […]
The post Adversarial learning breakthrough enables real-time AI security appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:12:05 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/adversarial-learning-breakthrough-real-time-ai-security/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Tech Get Rid of Bad Trips?</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-can-tech-get-rid-of-bad-trips/</link>
      <description>In this episode of Uncanny Valley, we talk about some of the latest drug trends and all the ways drugs are changing as they continue to be intertwined with tech.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-can-tech-get-rid-of-bad-trips/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>e-Conomy SEA 2025: Malaysia takes 32% of regional AI funding</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/malaysia-ai-investment-32-percent-sea-funding-2025/</link>
      <description>Malaysia has captured 32% of Southeast Asia’s total AI funding – equivalent to US$759 million – between H2 2024 and H1 2025, establishing itself as the region’s dominant destination for artificial intelligence investment as massive infrastructure expansion and high consumer adoption converge to reshape the country’s technology landscape, according to the e-Conomy SEA 2025 report […]
The post e-Conomy SEA 2025: Malaysia takes 32% of regional AI funding appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/malaysia-ai-investment-32-percent-sea-funding-2025/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZAYA1: AI model using AMD GPUs for training hits milestone</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/zaya1-ai-model-using-amd-gpus-for-training-hits-milestone/</link>
      <description>Zyphra, AMD, and IBM spent a year testing whether AMD’s GPUs and platform can support large-scale AI model training, and the result is ZAYA1. In partnership, the three companies trained ZAYA1 – described as the first major Mixture-of-Experts foundation model built entirely on AMD GPUs and networking – which they see as proof that the […]
The post ZAYA1: AI model using AMD GPUs for training hits milestone appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:07:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/zaya1-ai-model-using-amd-gpus-for-training-hits-milestone/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Is Using Specialized AI Agents for Deep Bug Hunting</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/amazon-autonomous-threat-analysis/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/amazon-autonomous-threat-analysis/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google commits to 1000x more AI infrastructure in next 4-5 years</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-commits-to-1000x-more-ai-infrastructure-in-next-4-5-years/</link>
      <description>In order to meet the massive demand for AI, Google wants to double the overall size of its servers every six months, a growth rate that would create a 1000x greater capacity in the next four or five years. The statement came from the head of Google’s AI infrastructure, Amin Vahdat, during an all-hands meeting […]
The post Google commits to 1000x more AI infrastructure in next 4-5 years appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:48:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-commits-to-1000x-more-ai-infrastructure-in-next-4-5-years/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Europe’s talent can secure a trillion-euro AI economic injection</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-europe-talent-can-secure-trillion-euro-ai-economic-injection/</link>
      <description>A €1.2 trillion AI prize sits on the table for Europe’s economy, and the region has the talent and raw ingredients to claim it. While the global narrative often focuses on competition with the US and China, the view from the ground in Europe is a region of untapped potential, world-class talent, and deep infrastructure […]
The post How Europe’s talent can secure a trillion-euro AI economic injection appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:03:53 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-europe-talent-can-secure-trillion-euro-ai-economic-injection/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APAC enterprises move AI infrastructure to edge as inference costs rise</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/enterprises-are-rethinking-ai-infrastructure-as-inference-costs-rise/</link>
      <description>AI spending in Asia Pacific continues to rise, yet many companies still struggle to get value from their AI projects. Much of this comes down to the infrastructure that supports AI, as most systems are not built to run inference at the speed or scale real applications need. Industry studies show many projects miss their […]
The post APAC enterprises move AI infrastructure to edge as inference costs rise appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/enterprises-are-rethinking-ai-infrastructure-as-inference-costs-rise/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Research Leader Behind ChatGPT’s Mental Health Work Is Leaving OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-research-lead-mental-health-quietly-departs/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-research-lead-mental-health-quietly-departs/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A $100 Billion Chip Project Forced a 91-Year-Old Woman From Her Home</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/micron-superfab-evicts-91-year-old-new-york/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/micron-superfab-evicts-91-year-old-new-york/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe Is Bending the Knee to the US on Tech Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/europe-bends-us-digital-policies-eu-ai-act/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/europe-bends-us-digital-policies-eu-ai-act/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>