<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 09:04:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>WIRED Roundup: Are We In An AI Bubble?</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-wired-roundup-are-we-in-an-ai-bubble/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 19:50:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-wired-roundup-are-we-in-an-ai-bubble/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta Tells Its Metaverse Workers to Use AI to ‘Go 5X Faster’</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/meta-mark-zuckerberg-ai-push-metaverse/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/meta-mark-zuckerberg-ai-push-metaverse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gemini Enterprise: Google aims to put an AI agent on every desk</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/gemini-enterprise-google-ai-agent-every-desk/</link>
      <description>Google Cloud has launched Gemini Enterprise, a new platform it calls “the new front door for AI in the workplace”. Announced during a virtual press conference, the platform brings together Google’s Gemini models, first and third-party agents, and the core technology of what was formerly known as Google Agentspace to create a singular agentic platform. […]
The post Gemini Enterprise: Google aims to put an AI agent on every desk appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:00:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/gemini-enterprise-google-ai-agent-every-desk/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI Slur ‘Clanker’ Has Become a Cover for Racist TikTok Skits</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-ai-slur-clanker-has-become-a-cover-for-racist-tiktok-skits/</link>
      <description>The online trend takes a comedic approach to spreading anti-AI messaging, but some creators are using racist references to make their point.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/the-ai-slur-clanker-has-become-a-cover-for-racist-tiktok-skits/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Cisco’s new AI data centre router tackle the industry’s biggest infrastructure bottleneck?</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/cisco-ai-data-centre-router-infrastructure-bottleneck/</link>
      <description>Cisco has entered an increasingly competitive race to dominate AI data centre interconnect technology, becoming the latest major player to unveil purpose-built routing hardware for connecting distributed AI workloads across multiple facilities. The networking giant unveiled its 8223 routing system on October 8, introducing what it claims is the industry’s first 51.2 terabit per second fixed router […]
The post Can Cisco’s new AI data centre router tackle the industry’s biggest infrastructure bottleneck? appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/cisco-ai-data-centre-router-infrastructure-bottleneck/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI value remains elusive despite soaring investment</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-value-remains-elusive-despite-soaring-investment/</link>
      <description>A new report from Red Hat finds that 89 percent of businesses are yet to see any customer value from their AI endeavours. However, organisations anticipate a 32 percent increase in AI investment by 2026. The survey finds that AI and security are the joint top IT priorities for UK organisations over the next 18 […]
The post AI value remains elusive despite soaring investment appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:00:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-value-remains-elusive-despite-soaring-investment/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fans Call on Taylor Swift to ‘Do Better’ After Accusations of Using AI for Promo Videos</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/taylor-swift-swifties-against-ai-viral/</link>
      <description>A scavenger hunt campaign to promote Taylor Swift’s new album, The Life of a Showgirl, resulted in a viral #SwiftiesAgainstAI campaign.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 20:53:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/taylor-swift-swifties-against-ai-viral/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Startup Wants to Spark a US DeepSeek Moment</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/prime-intellect-startup-us-deepseek-moment/</link>
      <description>With the US falling behind on open source models, one startup has a bold idea for democratizing AI: let anyone run reinforcement learning.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/prime-intellect-startup-us-deepseek-moment/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung’s tiny AI model beats giant reasoning LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/samsung-tiny-ai-model-beats-giant-reasoning-llms/</link>
      <description>A new paper from a Samsung AI researcher explains how a small network can beat massive Large Language Models (LLMs) in complex reasoning. In the race for AI supremacy, the industry mantra has often been “bigger is better.” Tech giants have poured billions into creating ever-larger models, but according to Alexia Jolicoeur-Martineau of Samsung SAIL […]
The post Samsung’s tiny AI model beats giant reasoning LLMs appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:55:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/samsung-tiny-ai-model-beats-giant-reasoning-llms/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuned Global strengthens its leadership in music technology with the acquisition of Figaro.ai</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tuned-global-strengthens-its-leadership-in-music-technology-with-the-acquisition-of-figaro-ai/</link>
      <description>The acquisition underscores Tuned Global’s commitment to shaping the future of the music industry by empowering clients with innovative technology and unmatched execution, while continuing to support existing Figaro.ai customers. Wednesday, 8 October, 2025 — Tuned Global, the leading music and media technology platform, has today announced the acquisition of Figaro.ai (by FeedForward), a London-based […]
The post Tuned Global strengthens its leadership in music technology with the acquisition of Figaro.ai appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 10:37:29 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tuned-global-strengthens-its-leadership-in-music-technology-with-the-acquisition-of-figaro-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Redaction That Puts Privacy First: CaseGuard Studio Leading The Way</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-redaction-that-puts-privacy-first-caseguard-studio-leading-the-way/</link>
      <description>Law enforcement, law firms, hospitals, and financial institutions are asked every day to release records, which can contain highly sensitive details – including addresses, social security numbers, medical diagnoses, evidence footage, and children’s identities.To meet compliance and security requirements, staff spend hundreds of hours manually redacting sensitive information, yet when that process goes wrong, there can be costly consequences. Last year, healthcare company Advanced was fined £6 million for losing patient records that, among other details, contained information about how to gain entry to the homes of 890 care receivers. Even the smallest oversights can create unpleasant headlines and catastrophic fines.This is the reality of modern data handling: leaks can be catastrophic, and compliance frameworks like GDPR, HIPAA, and FERPA, plus FOIA requests, require more vigilance than manual redaction can provide. What organizations need is not more staff to ensure proper redaction, but tools that achieve it quickly, reliably, and securely.CaseGuard Studio, a US-based AI redaction &amp; investigation platform, has built software that automates this manual work with 98% accuracy. It can process thousands of files in minutes, working on data that’s kept securely on-premises of any file type, including video, audio, documents, and images.Why Manual Redaction No Longer WorksRedaction is not new, but the tools most people reach for were not built for the complexity of today’s compliance requirements. Adobe Acrobat, for example, offers text redaction but needs manual work on each document. Premiere’s video editing software requires frame-by-frame subject tracking for video redaction, which is slow and impractical. These solutions provide only limited capability and were never designed for departments that process a multitude of redactions on a weekly basis.CaseGuard Studio, by contrast, was purpose-built for just this challenge. It can detect 12 categories of PII (personally-identifiable information) in video and images, such as faces, license plates, notepads, and more. It tracks and redacts all PII without needing manual frame-by-frame intervention.For audio and documents, CaseGuard Studio supports over 30 PII types, like names, phone numbers, and addresses. Cus...</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 09:07:44 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-redaction-that-puts-privacy-first-caseguard-studio-leading-the-way/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Sneezes, and Software Firms Catch a Cold</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-chatgpt-docusign-saas-market/</link>
      <description>OpenAI revealed last week the custom AI tools it uses internally. The news sent some software companies into turmoil.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-chatgpt-docusign-saas-market/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI is changing the way we travel</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-ai-is-changing-the-way-we-travel/</link>
      <description>AI is reshaping how people plan and experience travel. From curated videos on Instagram Reels to booking engines that build entire itineraries in seconds, AI is becoming a powerful force in how journeys are imagined, booked, and lived. But this shift raises an important question: is AI giving travellers more freedom, or quietly steering their […]
The post How AI is changing the way we travel appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-ai-is-changing-the-way-we-travel/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of AI Isn&#x27;t Just Slop</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-future-of-ai-media-parody-of-the-apocalypse-guy-named-josh/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/the-future-of-ai-media-parody-of-the-apocalypse-guy-named-josh/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jony Ive Says He Wants His OpenAI Devices to ‘Make Us Happy’</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/sam-altman-and-jony-ives-ai-device-dev-day/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 01:19:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/sam-altman-and-jony-ives-ai-device-dev-day/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Wants ChatGPT to Be Your Future Operating System</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-dev-day-sam-altman-chatgpt-apps/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 19:34:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-dev-day-sam-altman-chatgpt-apps/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI&#x27;s Blockbuster AMD Deal Is a Bet on Near-Limitless Demand for AI</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-amd-deal-data-center-chips/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 18:31:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-amd-deal-data-center-chips/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 best AI observability tools in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/5-best-ai-observability-tools-in-2025/</link>
      <description>Guest author: Or Hillel, Green LampAI systems aren’t experimental anymore, they’re embedded in everyday decisions that affect millions. Yet as these models stretch into important spaces like real-time supply chain routing, medical diagnostics, and financial markets, something as simple as a stealthy data shift or an undetected anomaly can flip confident automation into costly breakdown or public embarrassment.This isn’t just a problem for data scientists or machine learning engineers. Today, product managers, compliance officers, and business leaders are realising that AI’s value doesn’t just hinge on building a high-performing model, but on deeply understanding how, why, and when these models behave the way they do once exposed to the messiness of the real world.Enter AI observability, a discipline that’s no longer an optional add-on, but a daily reality for teams committed to reliable, defensible, and scalable AI-driven products.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:00:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/5-best-ai-observability-tools-in-2025/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google’s new AI agent rewrites code to automate vulnerability fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-new-ai-agent-rewrites-code-automate-vulnerability-fixes/</link>
      <description>Google DeepMind has deployed a new AI agent designed to autonomously find and fix critical security vulnerabilities in software code. The system, aptly-named CodeMender, has already contributed 72 security fixes to established open-source projects in the last six months. Identifying and patching vulnerabilities is a notoriously difficult and time-consuming process, even with the aid of […]
The post Google’s new AI agent rewrites code to automate vulnerability fixes appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:56:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-new-ai-agent-rewrites-code-automate-vulnerability-fixes/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>