<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 09:04:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Is Silicon Valley Still the Tech Capital?</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-is-silicon-valley-still-the-tech-capital/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 18:45:06 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-is-silicon-valley-still-the-tech-capital/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CAMIA privacy attack reveals what AI models memorise</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/camia-privacy-attack-reveals-what-ai-models-memorise/</link>
      <description>Researchers have developed a new attack that reveals privacy vulnerabilities by determining whether your data was used to train AI models. The method, named CAMIA (Context-Aware Membership Inference Attack), was developed by researchers from Brave and the National University of Singapore and is far more effective than previous attempts at probing the ‘memory’ of AI […]
The post CAMIA privacy attack reveals what AI models memorise appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:17:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/camia-privacy-attack-reveals-what-ai-models-memorise/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethical cybersecurity practice reshapes enterprise security in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manageengine-ethical-cybersecurity-2025/</link>
      <description>When ransomware attacks like Akira and Ryuk began crippling organisations worldwide, the cybersecurity industry’s first instinct was predictable: build bigger walls, deploy more aggressive automated responses, and lock down everything. But there was a different problem emerging, according to Romanus Prabhu Raymond, Director of Technology at ManageEngine. The company’s customers were demanding aggressive containment features, […]
The post Ethical cybersecurity practice reshapes enterprise security in 2025 appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 08:20:45 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manageengine-ethical-cybersecurity-2025/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung benchmarks real productivity of enterprise AI models</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/samsung-benchmarks-real-productivity-enterprise-ai-models/</link>
      <description>Samsung is overcoming limitations of existing benchmarks to better assess the real-world productivity of AI models in enterprise settings. The new system, developed by Samsung Research and named TRUEBench, aims to address the growing disparity between theoretical AI performance and its actual utility in the workplace. As businesses worldwide accelerate their adoption of large language […]
The post Samsung benchmarks real productivity of enterprise AI models appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:49:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/samsung-benchmarks-real-productivity-enterprise-ai-models/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google’s Conversational Photo Editor Is the Rare AI Feature People Will Actually Use</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/google-photos-conversational-photo-editor/</link>
      <description>Google’s tool greatly simplifies photo editing; just tell your phone what changes you want in the photo, and it’ll execute them. It also hints at the coming leap in how we interact with computers.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/google-photos-conversational-photo-editor/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Huawei’s plan to make thousands of AI chips think like one computer</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/huawei-ai-chips-superpod-technology/</link>
      <description>Imagine connecting thousands of powerful AI chips scattered in dozens of server cabinets and making them work together as if they were a single, massive computer. That is exactly what Huawei demonstrated at HUAWEI CONNECT 2025, where the company unveiled a breakthrough in AI infrastructure architecture that could reshape how the world builds and scales […]
The post Inside Huawei’s plan to make thousands of AI chips think like one computer appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:23:08 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/huawei-ai-chips-superpod-technology/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta Poaches OpenAI Scientist to Help Lead AI Lab</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/meta-poaches-openai-researcher-yang-song/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 04:26:31 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/meta-poaches-openai-researcher-yang-song/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This AI-Powered Robot Keeps Going Even if You Attack It With a Chainsaw</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/this-ai-powered-robot-keeps-going-even-if-you-attack-it-with-a-chainsaw/</link>
      <description>A single AI model trained to control numerous robotic bodies can operate unfamiliar hardware and adapt eerily well to serious injuries.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/this-ai-powered-robot-keeps-going-even-if-you-attack-it-with-a-chainsaw/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI in retail: Adoption comes at high security cost</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/generative-ai-in-retail-adoption-high-security-cost/</link>
      <description>The retail industry is among the leaders in generative AI adoption, but a new report highlights the security costs that accompany it. According to cybersecurity firm Netskope, the retail sector has all but universally adopted the technology, with 95% of organisations now using generative AI applications. That’s a huge jump from 73% just a year […]
The post Generative AI in retail: Adoption comes at high security cost appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 16:16:39 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/generative-ai-in-retail-adoption-high-security-cost/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Startup Used AI to Make a Psychedelic Without the Trip</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/a-startup-used-ai-to-make-a-psychedelic-without-the-trip/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/a-startup-used-ai-to-make-a-psychedelic-without-the-trip/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI and Nvidia plan $100B chip deal for AI future</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-and-nvidia-plan-100-b-chip-deal-for-ai-future/</link>
      <description>OpenAI and Nvidia have signed a letter of intent for a $100B partnership that could reshape how AI systems are trained and deployed. The plan calls for at least 10 gigawatts of Nvidia hardware to support OpenAI’s next-generation AI infrastructure, which will train and run future models aimed at superintelligence. To support the rollout, Nvidia […]
The post OpenAI and Nvidia plan $100B chip deal for AI future appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-and-nvidia-plan-100-b-chip-deal-for-ai-future/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Governing the age of agentic AI: Balancing autonomy and accountability  </title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/governing-the-age-of-agentic-ai-balancing-autonomy-and-accountability/</link>
      <description>Author: Rodrigo Coutinho, Co-Founder and AI Product Manager at OutSystems AI has moved beyond pilot projects and future promises. Today, it’s embedded in industries, with more than three-quarters of organisations (78%) now using AI in at least one business function. The next leap, however, is agentic AI: systems that don’t just provide insights or automate […]
The post Governing the age of agentic AI: Balancing autonomy and accountability   appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 08:19:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/governing-the-age-of-agentic-ai-balancing-autonomy-and-accountability/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Teams Up With Oracle and SoftBank to Build 5 New Stargate Data Centers</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-oracle-softbank-data-center-stargate-us/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-oracle-softbank-data-center-stargate-us/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Martin Frederik, Snowflake: Data quality is key to AI-driven growth</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/martin-frederik-snowflake-data-quality-key-ai-driven-growth/</link>
      <description>As companies race to implement AI, many are finding that project success hinges directly on the quality of their data. This dependency is causing many ambitious initiatives to stall, never making it beyond the experimental proof-of-concept stage. So, what’s the secret to turning these experiments into real revenue generators? AI News caught up with Martin […]
The post Martin Frederik, Snowflake: Data quality is key to AI-driven growth appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 16:34:26 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/martin-frederik-snowflake-data-quality-key-ai-driven-growth/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why One VC Thinks Quantum Is a Bigger Unlock Than AGI</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/alexa-von-tobel-quantum-venture-capital/</link>
      <description>Venture capitalist Alexa von Tobel is ready to bet on quantum computing—starting with hardware.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/alexa-von-tobel-quantum-venture-capital/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public trust deficit is a major hurdle for AI growth</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/public-trust-deficit-major-hurdle-for-ai-growth/</link>
      <description>While politicians tout AI’s promise of growth and efficiency, a new report reveals a public trust deficit in the technology. Many are deeply sceptical, creating a major headache for governments’ plans. A deep dive by the Tony Blair Institute for Global Change (TBI) and Ipsos has put some hard numbers on this feeling of unease. […]
The post Public trust deficit is a major hurdle for AI growth appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 15:47:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/public-trust-deficit-major-hurdle-for-ai-growth/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How BMC can be the ‘orchestrator of orchestrators’ for enterprise agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-bmc-can-be-the-orchestrator-of-orchestrators-for-enterprise-agentic-ai/</link>
      <description>Agentic AI is, in the opinion of McKinsey, the way to ‘break out of the gen AI paradox.’  Nearly four in five companies are using generative AI, according to the consultancy giant’s research, but comparatively few are getting any bottom-line value from it. The answer to the question of value, therefore, may be in orchestration. […]
The post How BMC can be the ‘orchestrator of orchestrators’ for enterprise agentic AI appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:00:45 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-bmc-can-be-the-orchestrator-of-orchestrators-for-enterprise-agentic-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Louisiana Hands Meta a Tax Break and Power for Its Biggest Data Center</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/louisiana-hands-meta-a-tax-break-and-power-for-its-biggest-data-center/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/louisiana-hands-meta-a-tax-break-and-power-for-its-biggest-data-center/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Thought I Knew Silicon Valley. I Was Wrong</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/silicon-valley-politics-shift/</link>
      <description>Tech got what it wanted by electing Trump. A year later, it looks more like a suicide pact.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/silicon-valley-politics-shift/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Tech Dreams of Putting Data Centers in Space</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/data-centers-gobble-earths-resources-what-if-we-took-them-to-space-instead/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/data-centers-gobble-earths-resources-what-if-we-took-them-to-space-instead/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>