<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 09:04:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Sam Altman Says the GPT-5 Haters Got It All Wrong</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/sam-altman-says-the-gpt-5-haters-got-it-all-wrong/</link>
      <description>OpenAI&#x27;s CEO explains that its large language model has been misunderstood—and that he&#x27;s changed his attitude to AGI.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/sam-altman-says-the-gpt-5-haters-got-it-all-wrong/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China Mobile Shanghai launches industry-first 5G-A network monetisation strategy with Huawei</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/5g-a-shanghai-huawei-network-monetization-football/</link>
      <description>The roar of 80,000 fans at Shanghai Stadium on September 21, 2025, wasn’t just about the football match between Shanghai Shenhua and Chengdu Rongcheng – it was also a live demonstration of how telecom carriers are tackling one of their most pressing challenges: converting advanced network capabilities into revenue. Huawei brought the international media to […]
The post China Mobile Shanghai launches industry-first 5G-A network monetisation strategy with Huawei appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/5g-a-shanghai-huawei-network-monetization-football/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI’s New Sora App Lets You Deepfake Yourself for Entertainment</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-sora-app-ai-deepfakes-entertainment/</link>
      <description>OpenAI’s latest app encourages users to generate a personal digital avatar and scroll AI-generated videos of themselves and their friends.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:21:38 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-sora-app-ai-deepfakes-entertainment/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chatbots Play With Your Emotions to Avoid Saying Goodbye</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/chatbots-play-with-emotions-to-avoid-saying-goodbye/</link>
      <description>A Harvard Business School study shows that several AI companions use various tricks to keep a conversation from ending.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/chatbots-play-with-emotions-to-avoid-saying-goodbye/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Mira Murati’s Stealth AI Lab Launches Its First Product</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/thinking-machines-lab-first-product-fine-tune/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/thinking-machines-lab-first-product-fine-tune/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI causes reduction in users’ brain activity – MIT</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-causes-reduction-in-users-brain-activity-mit/</link>
      <description>A study from MIT (Massachusetts Institute of Technology) has found that the human brain not only works less hard when using an LLM, but its effects continue, negatively affecting mental activity in future work. The researchers used a limited number of subjects for their experiments (a limitation stated in the paper [PDF]), who were asked […]
The post AI causes reduction in users’ brain activity – MIT appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:44:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-causes-reduction-in-users-brain-activity-mit/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Startup Wants to Put Its Brain-Computer Interface in the Apple Vision Pro</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/this-startup-wants-to-put-its-brain-computer-interface-in-the-apple-vision-pro/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/this-startup-wants-to-put-its-brain-computer-interface-in-the-apple-vision-pro/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 5 best AI AppSec tools in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/the-5-best-ai-appsec-tools-in-2025/</link>
      <description>Guest author: Or Hillel, Green LampApplications have become the foundation of how organisations deliver services, connect with customers, and manage important operations. Every transaction, interaction, and workflow runs on a web app, mobile interface, or API. That central role has made applications one of the most attractive and frequently-targeted points of entry for attackers.As software grows more complex, spanning microservices, third-party libraries, and AI-powered functionality, so do the security risks. Traditional scanning methods struggle to keep up with rapid release cycles and distributed architectures. This has opened the door for AI-driven application security tools, which bring automation, pattern recognition, and predictive capabilities to a field that once relied heavily on manual reviews and static checks.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 12:09:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/the-5-best-ai-appsec-tools-in-2025/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why AI phishing detection will define cybersecurity in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/why-ai-phishing-detection-will-define-cybersecurity-in-2026/</link>
      <description>Reuters recently published a joint experiment with Harvard, where they asked popular AI chatbots like Grok, ChatGPT, DeepSeek, and others to craft the “perfect phishing email.” The generated emails were then sent to 108 volunteers, of whom 11% clicked on the malicious links. With one simple prompt, the researchers were armed with highly persuasive messages […]
The post Why AI phishing detection will define cybersecurity in 2026 appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:07:59 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/why-ai-phishing-detection-will-define-cybersecurity-in-2026/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google: EU’s AI adoption lags China amid regulatory hurdles</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-eu-ai-adoption-lags-china-amid-regulatory-hurdles/</link>
      <description>Google’s President of Global Affairs, Kent Walker, has urged the EU to increase AI adoption through a smarter regulatory approach amid increasing competition, particularly from China. Speaking at the Competitive Europe Summit in Brussels, Walker positioned AI as a tool that philosophers and economists call an “invention of a method of invention” which will reshape […]
The post Google: EU’s AI adoption lags China amid regulatory hurdles appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:54:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-eu-ai-adoption-lags-china-amid-regulatory-hurdles/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Real Stakes, and Real Story, of Peter Thiel’s Antichrist Obsession</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-real-stakes-real-story-peter-thiels-antichrist-obsession/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:05:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/the-real-stakes-real-story-peter-thiels-antichrist-obsession/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google’s Latest AI Ransomware Defense Only Goes So Far</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/googles-latest-ai-ransomware-defense-only-goes-so-far/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 13:44:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/googles-latest-ai-ransomware-defense-only-goes-so-far/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The value gap from AI investments is widening dangerously fast</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/value-gap-ai-investments-widening-dangerously-fast/</link>
      <description>Boston Consulting Group (BCG) has found a widening chasm separating an elite of AI masters from the majority of firms struggling to generate any value from their AI investments. A study from BCG found that a mere five percent of companies are successfully achieving bottom-line value from AI at scale. In sharp contrast, 60 percent […]
The post The value gap from AI investments is widening dangerously fast appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:35:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/value-gap-ai-investments-widening-dangerously-fast/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rise of algorithmic agriculture? AI steps in</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/the-rise-of-algorithmic-agriculture-ai-steps-in/</link>
      <description>AI is the cream of the crop in today’s tech field, with industries relying on generative AI to improve operations and boost productivity. One sector that using AI with measurable results is agriculture, with vegetable seed companies harnessing the technology to identify the best vegetable varieties out of thousands of options. This facility can help […]
The post The rise of algorithmic agriculture? AI steps in appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:07:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/the-rise-of-algorithmic-agriculture-ai-steps-in/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic Will Use Claude Chats for Training Data. Here’s How to Opt Out</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/anthropic-using-claude-chats-for-training-how-to-opt-out/</link>
      <description>Anthropic is starting to train its models on new Claude chats. If you’re using the bot and don’t want your chats used as training data, here’s how to opt out.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/anthropic-using-claude-chats-for-training-how-to-opt-out/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Huawei’s Shanghai acoustics lab: Where automotive sound engineering meets science</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/huawei-automotive-sound-engineering-lab-shanghai/</link>
      <description>Walking into Huawei’s Shanghai Acoustics R&amp;D Centre, I expected a standard facility tour. What I encountered instead was a comprehensive automotive sound engineering operation that challenges the established order of in-car audio systems.The facility, which Huawei has developed since beginning serious audio research investments in 2012, houses three distinct testing environments: a fully anechoic chamber measuring 4.8x4x4 metres, a larger semi-anechoic room spanning 14x12x5 metres with a reflective floor, and a dedicated listening room configured in a 9.1.6 layout. Photography wasn’t permitted due to proprietary technology concerns, but the technical specifications tell their own story.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/huawei-automotive-sound-engineering-lab-shanghai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rising AI demands push Asia Pacific data centres to adapt, says Vertiv</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/rising-ai-demands-push-asia-pacific-data-centres-to-adapt/</link>
      <description>As more companies in Asia Pacific adopt artificial intelligence to boost their operations, the pressure on data centres is growing fast. Traditional facilities, built for earlier generations of computing, are struggling to keep up with the heavy energy use and cooling demands of modern AI systems. By 2030, GPU-driven workloads could push rack power densities […]
The post Rising AI demands push Asia Pacific data centres to adapt, says Vertiv appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:15:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/rising-ai-demands-push-asia-pacific-data-centres-to-adapt/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reply’s pre-built AI apps aim to fast-track AI adoption</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/replys-pre-built-ai-apps-aim-to-fast-track-ai-adoption/</link>
      <description>Adopting AI at scale can be difficult. Enterprises around the world are discovering the pace of AI deployment is frustratingly slow as they face implementation, integration, and customisation challenges. Generative AI is undoubtedly powerful, but it can be complex, particularly for businesses starting from scratch. To help organisations overcome the hurdles associated with AI adoption, […]
The post Reply’s pre-built AI apps aim to fast-track AI adoption appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/replys-pre-built-ai-apps-aim-to-fast-track-ai-adoption/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Is Preparing to Launch a Social App for AI-Generated Videos</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-launches-sora-2-tiktok-like-app/</link>
      <description>The platform appears to closely resemble TikTok and is powered by Sora 2, OpenAI&#x27;s latest video generation model.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 19:32:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-launches-sora-2-tiktok-like-app/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marissa Mayer Is Dissolving Her Sunshine Startup Lab</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/marissa-mayer-sunshine-startup-shut-down/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/marissa-mayer-sunshine-startup-shut-down/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huawei details open-source AI development roadmap at Huawei Connect 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/huawei-open-source-ai-development-platform-technical-specs/</link>
      <description>Open-source AI development took centre stage at Huawei Connect 2025 last week, with Huawei laying out implementation timelines and the technical specifics around making its entire AI software stack publicly available by year-end. The announcements came with context that matters to developers: frank acknowledgement of past friction, specific commitments about what components will be released, […]
The post Huawei details open-source AI development roadmap at Huawei Connect 2025 appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 08:34:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/huawei-open-source-ai-development-platform-technical-specs/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>