<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (PT &amp; EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
das últimas 24 horas, em Português e Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 02:23:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Salesforce Agentforce 3 brings visibility to AI agents</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/salesforce-agentforce-3-brings-visibility-ai-agents/</link>
      <description>Salesforce Agentforce 3 aims to tackle what many businesses have been struggling with: actually seeing what their AI agents are up to.Since its debut back in October 2024, Agentforce has been racking up some wins across a variety of sectors. Engine managed to slash customer case handling times by 15 percent, while 1-800Accountant handed off 70 percent of administrative chat queries to AI during the madness of tax season.But what’s interesting about this upgrade isn’t just the numbers, it’s how Salesforce is addressing the elephant in the room that nobody likes to talk about: businesses are deploying AI agents at breakneck speed without really understanding what they’re doing or how to improve them.Keeping tabs on your agentsThe centrepiece of Agentforce 3 is what Salesforce calls the Command Center (essentially a mission control for your AI employees.) It lets managers peek under the bonnet to spot patterns in how agents are performing, track health metrics in real-time (latency, escalation rates, errors), and identify which bits are working versus which need a swift kick.For anyone who’s ever deployed AI tools and then wondered “now what?” this level of visibility could be game-changing. The system captures all agent activity using the OpenTelemetry standard, which means it plays nicely with tools like Datadog and Splunk that your IT team probably already has on their screens.AI adoption is absolutely skyrocketing. Forthcoming data from the Slack Workflow Index shows AI agent usage up 233 percent in just six months. During that time, about 8,000 organisations signed up to deploy Agentforce.Ryan Teeples, CTO at 1-800Accountant, said: “Agentforce autonomously resolved 70% of 1-800Accountant’s administrative chat engagements during the peak of this past tax season, an incredible lift during one of our busiest periods. But that early success was just the beginning.“We’ve established a strong deployment foundation and weekly are focused on launching new agentic experiences and AI automations through Agentforce’s newest capabilities. With a high level of observability, we can see what’s working, optimise in real time, and scale support with confidence.”Salesforce Agentforce 3 doesn’t just provide data, it actually suggests improvements. The AI effectively watche...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 17:10:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/salesforce-agentforce-3-brings-visibility-ai-agents/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huawei HarmonyOS 6 AI agents offer alternative to Android and iOS</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/huawei-harmonyos-6-ai-agents-beta/</link>
      <description>The latest phase of the mobile OS wars isn’t being fought over app stores or user interfaces – it’s being waged with artificial intelligence. Huawei’s latest salvo comes in the form of HarmonyOS 6, in which AI agents aren’t features but the architecture driving user interactions.The beta release to developers signals a broader industry shift where operating systems transform from passive platforms into what are being framed as intelligent intermediaries that anticipate, learn, and act on behalf of users.The AI-first approach defines the latest releaseThe centrepiece of HarmonyOS 6 lies in its AI agents framework, which lets developers create automated programmes without the complexity of building or training foundation models from scratch.The HarmonyOS Agent Framework attempts to make AI development more accessible in Huawei’s ecosystem.Richard Yu Chengdong, chairman of Huawei’s consumer business group, has announced that more than 50 AI agents from established Chinese platforms including Weibo and Ximalaya will be available when HarmonyOS 6 launches to consumers.However, Yu did not specify a public release date during a developer conference presentation held on Friday.The AI agents integration develops an industry trend where operating systems become platforms for artificial intelligence deployment rather than application launchers. By embedding AI capabilities directly into the OS layer, Huawei positions HarmonyOS 6 as a foundation for what the company calls next-generation computing experiences.Ecosystem metrics show steady progressThe platform has eight million registered developers and hosts more than 30,000 applications and “atomic services” – lightweight programmes that run without installation. HarmonyOS 5 operates on more than 40 device models, indicating steady hardware adoption.Yu acknowledged the competitive landscape, stating that HarmonyOS still lags behind Apple’s iOS and Google’s Android in terms of global reach and application support.“But the top 5,000 apps accounted for 99.9 per cent of consumer time spent” on Huawei devices, he said, suggesting the company prioritises essential applications over total app quantity.The pragmatic approach reflects Huawei’s understanding that ecosystem success depends on quality and user engagement rather t...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 08:33:05 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/huawei-harmonyos-6-ai-agents-beta/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>