<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:05:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>WIRED Roundup: DOGE Isn’t Dead, Facebook Dating Is Real, and Amazon’s AI Ambitions</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-wired-roundup-doge-facebook-dating-amazon-artificial-intelligence/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 22:29:11 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-wired-roundup-doge-facebook-dating-amazon-artificial-intelligence/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here’s What You Should Know About Launching an AI Startup</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/artificial-intelligence-startups-daydream-fashion-recommendations/</link>
      <description>AI startups say the promise of turning dazzling models into useful products is harder than anyone expected. Three founders discuss what it takes.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/artificial-intelligence-startups-daydream-fashion-recommendations/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK and Germany plan to commercialise quantum supercomputing</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uk-and-germany-plan-to-commercialise-quantum-supercomputing/</link>
      <description>The UK and Germany plan to integrate their science sectors to accelerate the commercialisation of quantum supercomputing technology. Announced on the final day of the German president’s state visit, these joint commitments target the gap between R&amp;D and enterprise application in computing, sensing, and timing. The partnership involves specific funding to fast-track product development and […]
The post UK and Germany plan to commercialise quantum supercomputing appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:42:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uk-and-germany-plan-to-commercialise-quantum-supercomputing/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aluminium OS is the AI-powered successor to ChromeOS</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/aluminium-os-is-the-next-iteration-for-the-chromebook-range-chromeos-chrome-os/</link>
      <description>The convergence of mobile and desktop operating systems is a goal that has remained elusive for big tech firms since the early days of the smartphone. Microsoft’s attempt in the form of Windows Mobile was reaching the end of its road by 2010, and despite Apple’s iOS/iPadOS and macOS moving very slowly towards one another […]
The post Aluminium OS is the AI-powered successor to ChromeOS appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:32:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/aluminium-os-is-the-next-iteration-for-the-chromebook-range-chromeos-chrome-os/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Slop Is Ruining Reddit for Everyone</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/ai-slop-is-ruining-reddit-for-everyone/</link>
      <description>Reddit is considered one of the most human spaces left on the internet, but mods and users are overwhelmed with slop posts in the most popular subreddits.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/ai-slop-is-ruining-reddit-for-everyone/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huge Trove of Nude Images Leaked by AI Image Generator Startup’s Exposed Database</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/huge-trove-of-nude-images-leaked-by-ai-image-generator-startups-exposed-database/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/huge-trove-of-nude-images-leaked-by-ai-image-generator-startups-exposed-database/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can AI Look at Your Retina and Diagnose Alzheimer’s? Eric Topol Hopes So</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/big-interview-event-eric-topol-super-agers/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 23:11:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/big-interview-event-eric-topol-super-agers/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic’s Daniela Amodei Believes the Market Will Reward Safe AI</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/big-interview-event-daniela-amodei-anthropic/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 21:40:38 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/big-interview-event-daniela-amodei-anthropic/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Happens When Your Coworkers Are AI Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-what-happens-when-your-coworkers-are-ai-agents/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 21:03:59 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-what-happens-when-your-coworkers-are-ai-agents/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jon M. Chu Says AI Couldn’t Have Made One of the Best Moments in ‘Wicked’</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/big-interview-event-jon-chu-wicked/</link>
      <description>The Wicked: For Good director says being able to improvise on set allows for the kind of moments that are hard for machines to make.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 20:18:26 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/big-interview-event-jon-chu-wicked/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD CEO Lisa Su Says Concerns About an AI Bubble Are Overblown</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/big-interview-event-lisa-su-amd/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:51:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/big-interview-event-lisa-su-amd/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ByteDance and DeepSeek Are Placing Very Different AI Bets</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/deepseek-goes-high-while-bytedance-goes-wide/</link>
      <description>The diverging path of China’s two leading AI players shows where the country’s artificial intelligence industry is headed.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:57:09 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/deepseek-goes-high-while-bytedance-goes-wide/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS re:Invent 2025: Frontier AI agents replace chatbots</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/aws-reinvent-2025-frontier-ai-agents-replace-chatbots/</link>
      <description>According to AWS at this week’s re:Invent 2025, the chatbot hype cycle is effectively dead, with frontier AI agents taking their place. That is the blunt message radiating from Las Vegas this week. The industry’s obsession with chat interfaces has been replaced by a far more demanding mandate: “frontier agents” that don’t just talk, but […]
The post AWS re:Invent 2025: Frontier AI agents replace chatbots appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:23:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/aws-reinvent-2025-frontier-ai-agents-replace-chatbots/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decart uses AWS Trainium3 for real-time video generation</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/decart-uses-aws-trainium3-for-real-time-video-generation/</link>
      <description>Amazon Web Services has scored another major win for its custom AWS Trainium accelerators after striking a deal with AI video startup Decart. The partnership will see Decart optimise its flagship Lucy model on AWS Trainium3 to support real-time video generation, and highlight the growing popularity of AI accelerators over Nvidia’s graphics processing units.Decart is essentially going all-in on AWS, and as part of the deal, the company will also make its models available through the Amazon Bedrock platform. Developers can integrate Decart’s real-time video generation capabilities into almost any cloud application without worrying about underlying infrastructure.The distribution through Bedrock increases AWS’s plug-and-play capabilities, demonstrating Amazon’s confidence in growing demand for real-time AI video. It also allows Decart to expand reach and grow adoption among the developer community. AWS Trainium provides Lucy with the extra processing grunt needed to generate high-fidelity video without sacrificing quality or latency.Custom AI accelerators like Trainium provide an alternative to Nvidia’s GPUs for AI workloads. While Nvidia still dominates the AI market, its GPUs processing the vast majority of AI workloads, it’s facing a growing threat from custom processors.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:19:09 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/decart-uses-aws-trainium3-for-real-time-video-generation/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI memory hunger forces Micron’s consumer exodus: A turning point in semiconductor economics</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-memory-hunger-micron-consumer-exit/</link>
      <description>In the basement of a Boise, Idaho, dental office in 1978, four engineers founded what would become one of America’s semiconductor giants. Ward Parkinson, Joe Parkinson, Dennis Wilson, and Doug Pitman started Micron Technology as a modest design consultancy, backed by local investors including potato magnate J.R. Simplot. By 1983, they had achieved a technological […]
The post AI memory hunger forces Micron’s consumer exodus: A turning point in semiconductor economics appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 06:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-memory-hunger-micron-consumer-exit/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI in manufacturing set to unleash new era of profit</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-in-manufacturing-set-to-unleash-new-era-of-profit/</link>
      <description>Manufacturing executives are wagering nearly half their modernisation budgets on AI, betting these systems will boost profit within two years. This aggressive capital allocation marks a definitive pivot. AI is now seen as the primary engine for financial performance. According to the Future-Ready Manufacturing Study 2025 by Tata Consultancy Services (TCS) and AWS, 88 percent […]
The post AI in manufacturing set to unleash new era of profit appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:30:04 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-in-manufacturing-set-to-unleash-new-era-of-profit/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB AI Range offers experiments in cyber-resilience training</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/htb-ai-range-testing-ai-security-in-sandbox-agentic-ai-experiments/</link>
      <description>The cybersecurity training provider Hack The Box (HTB) has launched the HTB AI Range, designed to let organisations test autonomous AI security agents under realistic conditions, albeit with oversight from human cybersecurity professionals. Its goal is to help users assess how well AI, and mixed human–AI teams might defend infrastructure. Vulnerabilities in AI models add […]
The post HTB AI Range offers experiments in cyber-resilience training appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:46:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/htb-ai-range-testing-ai-security-in-sandbox-agentic-ai-experiments/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EY and NVIDIA to help companies test and deploy physical AI</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ey-and-nvidia-to-help-companies-test-and-deploy-physical-ai/</link>
      <description>AI is moving deeper into the physical world, and EY is laying out a more structured way for companies to work with robots, drones, and other smart devices. The organisation is introducing a physical AI platform built with NVIDIA tools, opening a new EY.ai Lab in Georgia, and adding new leadership to guide its work […]
The post EY and NVIDIA to help companies test and deploy physical AI appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ey-and-nvidia-to-help-companies-test-and-deploy-physical-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic just revealed how AI-orchestrated cyberattacks actually work—Here’s what enterprises need to know</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-orchestrated-cyberattacks-anthropic-discovery/</link>
      <description>For years, cybersecurity experts debated when – not if – artificial intelligence would cross the threshold from advisor to autonomous attacker. That theoretical milestone has arrived. Anthropic’s recent investigation into a Chinese state-sponsored operation has documented [PDF] the first case of AI-orchestrated cyber attacks executing at scale with minimal human oversight, altering what enterprises must […]
The post Anthropic just revealed how AI-orchestrated cyberattacks actually work—Here’s what enterprises need to know appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-orchestrated-cyberattacks-anthropic-discovery/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singularity Compute launches Swedish GPU cluster amid the AI infrastructure crunch</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amidst-the-ongoing-ai-infrastructure-crunch-singularity-compute-launches-swedish-gpu-cluster/</link>
      <description>Since the surge in AI adoption over the last couple of months, it’s become clear there isn’t enough computational horsepower to go around (something that has become painfully obvious as cloud providers have accrued months-long waitlists for high-end GPU instances). Unlike the brief cryptocurrency-mining GPU craze a few years ago, today’s crunch is driven by real demand from AI research and deployments.For the sake of perspective, Amazon Web Services has been charging about $98 per hour for an 8-GPU server loaded with Nvidia’s top-tier H100 chips, while some decentralised GPU platforms offer comparable hardware for as little as $3 an hour. Amid this stark 30× price gap, Singularity Compute, the infrastructure arm of decentralised AI pioneer SingularityNET, has announced phase I deployment of its first enterprise-grade NVIDIA GPU cluster at a state-of-the-art data centre in Sweden.Under a partnership with Swedish operator Conapto, Singularity’s cluster is using cutting-edge NVIDIA hardware (including the next-generation H200 and L40S GPUs) in a Stockholm facility powered entirely by renewable energy.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 09:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amidst-the-ongoing-ai-infrastructure-crunch-singularity-compute-launches-swedish-gpu-cluster/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can China’s chip stacking strategy really challenge Nvidia’s AI dominance?</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/china-chip-stacking-strategy-nvidia/</link>
      <description>Chip stacking strategy is emerging as China’s innovative response to US semiconductor restrictions, but can this approach truly close the performance gap with Nvidia’s advanced GPUs? As Washington tightens export controls on cutting-edge chipmaking technology, Chinese researchers are proposing a bold workaround: stack older, domestically-producible chips together to match the performance of chips they can […]
The post Can China’s chip stacking strategy really challenge Nvidia’s AI dominance? appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/china-chip-stacking-strategy-nvidia/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frontier AI research lab tackles enterprise deployment challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/frontier-ai-research-lab-tackles-enterprise-deployment-challenges/</link>
      <description>Thomson Reuters and Imperial College London have established a frontier AI research lab to overcome historic deployment challenges. Speed and scale have defined the current AI boom. But for enterprises, the primary obstacles to deployment are different: trust, accuracy, and lineage. Addressing these barriers, Thomson Reuters and Imperial College London have announced a five-year partnership […]
The post Frontier AI research lab tackles enterprise deployment challenges appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:26:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/frontier-ai-research-lab-tackles-enterprise-deployment-challenges/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>