<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 09:04:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>The White House Apparently Ordered Federal Workers to Roll Out Grok ‘ASAP’</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/white-house-elon-musk-xai-grok/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 13:22:26 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/white-house-elon-musk-xai-grok/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marketing AI boom faces crisis of consumer trust</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/marketing-ai-boom-faces-crisis-of-consumer-trust/</link>
      <description>The vast majority (92%) of marketing professionals are using AI in their day-to-day operations, turning it from a buzzword into a workhorse. According to SAP Emarsys – which took the pulse of over 10,000 consumers and 1,250 marketers – while businesses are seeing real benefits from AI, shoppers are becoming increasingly distrustful, especially when it […]
The post Marketing AI boom faces crisis of consumer trust appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 12:19:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/marketing-ai-boom-faces-crisis-of-consumer-trust/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch Our Livestream Replay: Back to School in the Age of AI</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/livestream-back-to-school-in-the-age-of-ai/</link>
      <description>We explored our latest investigations into how tech is shaping education today.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 21:28:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/livestream-back-to-school-in-the-age-of-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI security wars: Can Google Cloud defend against tomorrow’s threats?</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-security-wars-google-cloud-cybersecurity-threats/</link>
      <description>In Google’s sleek Singapore office at Block 80, Level 3, Mark Johnston stood before a room of technology journalists at 1:30 PM with a startling admission: after five decades of cybersecurity evolution, defenders are still losing the war. “In 69% of incidents in Japan and Asia Pacific, organisations were notified of their own breaches by […]
The post AI security wars: Can Google Cloud defend against tomorrow’s threats? appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 11:02:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-security-wars-google-cloud-cybersecurity-threats/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agentic AI: Promise, scepticism, and its meaning for Southeast Asia</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/agentic-ai-promise-scepticism-and-its-meaning-for-southeast-asia/</link>
      <description>Agentic AI is being talked about as the next major wave of artificial intelligence, but its meaning for enterprises remains to be settled. Capgemini Research Institute estimates agentic AI could unlock as much as US$450 billion in economic value by 2028. Yet adoption is still limited: only 2% of organisations have scaled its use, and […]
The post Agentic AI: Promise, scepticism, and its meaning for Southeast Asia appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 10:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/agentic-ai-promise-scepticism-and-its-meaning-for-southeast-asia/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tencent Hunyuan Video-Foley brings lifelike audio to AI video</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tencent-hunyuan-video-foley-lifelike-audio-to-ai-video/</link>
      <description>A team at Tencent’s Hunyuan lab has created a new AI, ‘Hunyuan Video-Foley,’ that finally brings lifelike audio to generated video. It’s designed to listen to videos and generate a high-quality soundtrack that’s perfectly in sync with the action on screen. Ever watched an AI-generated video and felt like something was missing? The visuals might […]
The post Tencent Hunyuan Video-Foley brings lifelike audio to AI video appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 08:43:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tencent-hunyuan-video-foley-lifelike-audio-to-ai-video/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Rollup News says about battling disinformation</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/what-rollup-news-says-about-battling-disinformation/</link>
      <description>Swarm Network, a platform developing decentralised protocols for AI agents, recently announced the successful results of its first Swarm, a tool (perhaps “organism” is the better term) built to tackle disinformation. Called Rollup News, the swarm is not an app, a software platform, nor a centralised algorithm. It is a decentralised collection of AI agents that collaborate to solve a bigger problem. The problem is that platforms like X allow any type of viral claims, some by incredibly influential people. How can we know what is true?Currently, we try to solve this problem through equally loud opposing voices who offer facts or expert opinions. But if those sources are from a political side you oppose, why should you trust them? After all, these are people with their own motivations, and two additional issues are created: facts presented by a single person can easily get caught up in the “fake news” accusations; and misinformation presented as “facts” can be used to attack the ground truth.Unfortunately, this isn’t just a current trend that will eventually lose its popularity and fade out. The more technology and access to varied news sources we have, the harder it becomes to not treat these sources equally. Some might be a traditional outlet that is legally liable if they falsify claims. Others might be a popular podcaster with an audience of millions, and whose fear-mongering ties nicely in with the products in their merch store. If it stopped at this, we could probably tell the truth from fiction. But it isn’t that simple. Official news channels have a history of spinning the news in their own bias, or ignoring other stories that are important to the public. On the other side, there are genuinely powerful influencers who seem to be hell bent on finding the truth and reporting it, no matter what side of the political spectrum it hits.The world has become both confusing and dangerous, and the old “sticks and stones” saying has been proven false. After all, we have seen global elections swayed by disinformation, major policy shifts driven by false claims, lives damaged and lost as the result of powerful people lying, but lying loudly enough and often enough to sway large groups of people into believing them; and convincing these same groups that any facts to...</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 07:41:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/what-rollup-news-says-about-battling-disinformation/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Vids gets AI avatars and image-to-video tools</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-vids-gets-ai-avatars-and-image-to-video-tools/</link>
      <description>Google is rolling out a raft of powerful new generative AI features for Vids designed to take the pain out of video creation.Between wrestling with complicated software, finding someone willing to be on camera, and then spending hours editing out all the “ums” and “ahs,” video production often feels more trouble than it’s worth. Google is aiming to change that narrative with Vids.So far, it seems to be finding its audience. Google announced that Vids has already rocketed past one million monthly active users, a clear sign that teams are crying out for simpler ways to bring their ideas to life with video.Your photos now move, and avatars do the talkingAmong the latest additions is the ability to turn static images into motion pictures. Imagine you’ve got a great photo of a new product but need something more engaging for a social media post or presentation. You can now upload that picture to Vids, type a quick prompt describing what you want to happen, and Google’s Veo AI will turn it into an eight-second animated clip, complete with sound. It’s a simple way to create eye-catching, brand-aligned content in minutes.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 14:48:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-vids-gets-ai-avatars-and-image-to-video-tools/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Era of AI-Generated Ransomware Has Arrived</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-era-of-ai-generated-ransomware-has-arrived/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 12:36:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/the-era-of-ai-generated-ransomware-has-arrived/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zopa: AI to automate banking, threaten finance jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/zopa-ai-automate-banking-threaten-finance-jobs/</link>
      <description>AI is transforming the banking industry, but the expected benefits and savings come at great human cost with the impact on finance jobs. The report, a collaboration between digital bank Zopa and Juniper Research, forecasts that generative AI will deliver £1.8 billion in cost savings by 2030, driven by an equivalent level of investment. However, […]
The post Zopa: AI to automate banking, threaten finance jobs appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 11:49:58 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/zopa-ai-automate-banking-threaten-finance-jobs/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decentralised AI: Full of promise, but not without challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/decentralised-ai-full-of-promise-but-not-without-challenges/</link>
      <description>Decentralised artificial intelligence has been hailed as one of the most profound innovations of our time, promising to give users control of the most transformative technologies. Yet the industry faces some daunting challenges if the vision is to be fulfilled.Proponents of decentralisation imagine a world where AI is not controlled by a select few big tech corporations, but rather by a global community that invites everyone to participate and have their say. It’s an audacious goal, but as it slowly comes into view, a question arises – are we really on the cusp of democratising access to intelligent automation, or are we creating a recipe for disaster?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 10:24:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/decentralised-ai-full-of-promise-but-not-without-challenges/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic Settles High-Profile AI Copyright Lawsuit Brought by Book Authors</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/anthropic-settles-copyright-lawsuit-authors/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 19:31:59 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/anthropic-settles-copyright-lawsuit-authors/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Researchers Are Already Leaving Meta’s New Superintelligence Lab</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/researchers-leave-meta-superintelligence-labs-openai/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 18:00:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/researchers-leave-meta-superintelligence-labs-openai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI’s dual nature: Genuine innovation amid localised bubbles</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ais-dual-nature-genuine-innovation-amid-localised-bubbles/</link>
      <description>AI’s growing dominance in the world, whether it be reshaping industries’ workflows or influencing investor portfolios, is redefining how society and economies evolve. Of course, the hype and buzz around AI has been and is hard to ignore, but the question is, does this hype often overshadow the real challenges and limitations of AI? According […]
The post AI’s dual nature: Genuine innovation amid localised bubbles appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 15:23:15 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ais-dual-nature-genuine-innovation-amid-localised-bubbles/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X and xAI sue Apple and OpenAI over AI monopoly claims</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/x-and-xai-sue-apple-and-openai-ai-monopoly-claims/</link>
      <description>Elon Musk’s X and xAI are taking on Apple and OpenAI, accusing the tech giants of an AI monopoly to crush their competition.A lawsuit by the companies filed in a Texas federal court claims the exclusive partnership between Apple and OpenAI to put ChatGPT on the iPhone is a calculated move by “two monopolists joining forces to ensure their continued dominance.”The deal to integrate ChatGPT deep into Apple’s operating system makes the world’s most renowned AI assistant currently the one and only to be able to control core iPhone features; effectively locking out rivals like xAI’s own chatbot, Grok.The lawsuit claims this denies users a fair choice, ironically quoting an OpenAI strategy document that states, “Real choice drives competition and benefits everyone. Users should be able to pick their Al assistant.”The real prize, according to the complaint, is data. Generative AI gets smarter and better with every user question, creating a powerful feedback loop.By giving ChatGPT exclusive access to potentially billions of prompts from hundreds of millions of iPhones, the partnership effectively builds an impenetrable “moat” around OpenAI’s market leadership. It starves competitors of the data they need to improve their own models and truly compete, thereby helping to sustain the alleged AI monopoly.So valuable is this stream of data, the lawsuit claims, that OpenAI is giving Apple its technology for free, considering the access “of equal or greater value than monetary payments.”As for why Apple would agree to this, the lawsuit argues it’s a defensive move against an existential threat: the rise of “super apps”. These all-in-one applications – like the one X is building, similar to popular Chinese platform WeChat – combine social media, messaging, payments, and other services into a single platform. As these super apps become more powerful with cloud-based AI services, they make the smartphone itself less important. Users could simply buy a cheaper phone and get all the functionality they need from the app, threatening Apple’s lucrative hardware sales.The complaint alleges Apple is acutely aware of this danger, citing one company manager who warned that letting super apps take over would be like letting “the barbarians in at the gate.”But the allegations don’t sto...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 12:52:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/x-and-xai-sue-apple-and-openai-ai-monopoly-claims/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top AI vibe-coding platforms powering Web3 builds</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/top-ai-vibe-coding-platforms-powering-web3-builds/</link>
      <description>Vibe coding is making lots of noise in software development, but perhaps nowhere will its presence be felt more keenly than in the Web3 coding space.Of course, not every AI code generator is cut out for Web3 development. That’s because it’s a niche area that requires deep expertise in blockchain languages and smart contract frameworks. So the most popular vibe coding platforms, like Cursor, Devin, and GitHub’s CoPilot are out of the question when it comes to automating smart contract creation. But fortunately, there are a number of Web3-specific coding tools emerging that promise to turbocharge blockchain automation.The beauty of Web3 vibe coding tools is that they can abstract away much of the complexity of blockchain and smart contracts, opening the doors for many more developers to participate in building decentralised applications.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 09:26:51 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/top-ai-vibe-coding-platforms-powering-web3-builds/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alexis Ohanian’s Next Social Platform Has One Rule: Don’t Act Like an Asshole</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-big-interview-alexis-ohanian/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-big-interview-alexis-ohanian/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaysia launches Ryt Bank, its first AI-powered bank</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/malaysia-launches-ryt-bank-its-first-ai-powered-bank/</link>
      <description>AI is steadily changing the way banks work. The technology can sift through massive amounts of data, calculate risks, and handle routine tasks at speeds people can’t match. Now, Malaysia has entered that space with the launch of Ryt Bank, billed as the first AI-powered bank created in the country.The new venture, led by YTL Group in partnership with Sea Limited, arrives just ahead of Merdeka. “Ryt Bank demonstrates that groundbreaking innovation can be imagined, built, and led right here in Malaysia,” said Dato’ Seri Yeoh Seok Hong, Managing Director of YTL Power International. “By combining homegrown AI with the values and diversity of our people, we’ve created a bank that Malaysians can proudly call their own – one that speaks our languages, understands our culture, and sets a new standard for how banking should feel.”Banking for MalaysiansRyt Bank has been designed to work in the languages most Malaysians use every day. Its app is already available in Bahasa Malaysia and English, with Mandarin support scheduled to arrive by next month (September 2025). By offering multilingual access, the bank aims to make financial services more inclusive and easy to use for people in many different communities.The centrepiece of the AI-powered bank is Ryt AI, a digital assistant powered by ILMU, Malaysia’s first locally-developed large language model. Ryt AI can understand natural conversation – in Bahasa Malaysia, English, or a mixture of both – and act on requests instantly.The AI assistant can read and pay bills, track spending, and explain financial basics in plain terms. The idea is to blend convenience with cultural familiarity, while maintaining enterprise-grade security.Everyday AI banking in one appRyt Bank is designed to pull together multiple financial needs into one platform. Customers can use the AI bank app to save, spend, borrow, and pay bills, with Ryt AI making the process more conversational and personal.Personal banking with Ryt AISend money or pay bills through text chat, with support for DuitNow and JomPAY.Snap and upload bills or receipts for instant payment.Access guides and simple financial explanations as you bank.All actions are encrypted and verified for security.New users can claim a small launch reward of up to RM5 when they try Ryt AI.Grow...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 08:15:39 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/malaysia-launches-ryt-bank-its-first-ai-powered-bank/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Is Eliminating Jobs for Younger Workers</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/stanford-research-ai-replace-jobs-young-workers/</link>
      <description>New research from Stanford provides the clearest available evidence that AI is reshaping the workforce—but it’s complicated.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/stanford-research-ai-replace-jobs-young-workers/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk’s xAI Sues Apple and OpenAI Over App Store Rankings</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musks-xai-sues-apple-and-openai-over-alleged-app-store-rigging/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 16:57:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musks-xai-sues-apple-and-openai-over-alleged-app-store-rigging/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM and NASA Develop a Digital Twin of the Sun to Predict Future Solar Storms</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/ibm-and-nasa-develop-a-digital-twin-of-the-sun-to-predict-future-solar-storms/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/ibm-and-nasa-develop-a-digital-twin-of-the-sun-to-predict-future-solar-storms/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Ingredients Behind AI’s Creativity</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/researchers-uncover-hidden-ingredients-behind-ai-creativity/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/researchers-uncover-hidden-ingredients-behind-ai-creativity/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>