<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 09:04:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>The Data Center Resistance Has Arrived</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-data-center-resistance-has-arrived/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:43:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/the-data-center-resistance-has-arrived/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic details cyber espionage campaign orchestrated by AI</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/anthropic-details-cyber-espionage-campaign-orchestrated-by-ai/</link>
      <description>Security leaders face a new class of autonomous threat as Anthropic details the first cyber espionage campaign orchestrated by AI. In a report released this week, the company’s Threat Intelligence team outlined its disruption of a sophisticated operation by a Chinese state-sponsored group – an assessment made with high confidence – dubbed GTG-1002 and detected […]
The post Anthropic details cyber espionage campaign orchestrated by AI appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/anthropic-details-cyber-espionage-campaign-orchestrated-by-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Won’t Be Able to Offload Your Holiday Shopping to AI Agents Anytime Soon</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/inside-the-dealmaking-to-make-agentic-shopping-a-reality/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/inside-the-dealmaking-to-make-agentic-shopping-a-reality/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visa builds AI commerce infrastructure for the Asia Pacific’s 2026 Pilot</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/visa-ai-commerce-intelligent-commerce-2026/</link>
      <description>When Visa unveiled its Intelligent Commerce platform for Asia Pacific on November 12, it wasn’t just launching another payment feature—it was building AI commerce infrastructure to solve a crisis most merchants haven’t noticed yet: their websites are being flooded by AI agents, and there’s no reliable way to tell which ones are legitimate shoppers and which are malicious bots.  […]
The post Visa builds AI commerce infrastructure for the Asia Pacific’s 2026 Pilot appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/visa-ai-commerce-intelligent-commerce-2026/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM: Data silos are holding back enterprise AI</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ibm-data-silos-are-holding-back-enterprise-ai/</link>
      <description>According to IBM, the primary barrier holding back enterprise AI isn’t the technology itself but the persistent issue of data silos. Ed Lovely, VP and Chief Data Officer at IBM, describes data silos as the “Achilles’ heel” of modern data strategy. Lovely made the comments following the release of a new study from the IBM […]
The post IBM: Data silos are holding back enterprise AI appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 13:25:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ibm-data-silos-are-holding-back-enterprise-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Relationships Are on the Rise. A Divorce Boom Could Be Next</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/ai-relationships-are-on-the-rise-a-divorce-boom-could-be-next/</link>
      <description>Secret chatbot flings are creating new legal challenges for married couples when it comes to infidelity.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/ai-relationships-are-on-the-rise-a-divorce-boom-could-be-next/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI’s Open-Weight Models Are Coming to the US Military</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/open-ai-artificial-intelligence-open-weight-model/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/open-ai-artificial-intelligence-open-weight-model/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New data centre projects mark Anthropic’s biggest US expansion yet</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-data-centre-projects-mark-anthropic-biggest-us-expansion/</link>
      <description>New US data centre projects in Texas and New York will receive $50 billion in new funding, part of a plan to grow US computing capacity for advanced AI work. The facilities, built with Fluidstack, are designed for Anthropic’s systems and will focus on power and efficiency needs that come with training and running large […]
The post New data centre projects mark Anthropic’s biggest US expansion yet appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-data-centre-projects-mark-anthropic-biggest-us-expansion/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic’s Claude Takes Control of a Robot Dog</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/anthropic-claude-takes-control-robot-dog/</link>
      <description>Anthropic believes AI models will increasingly reach into the physical world. To understand where things are headed, it asked Claude to program a quadruped.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/anthropic-claude-takes-control-robot-dog/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI Boom Is Fueling a Need for Speed in Chip Networking</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/ai-boom-networking-technology-photonics/</link>
      <description>Next-gen networking tech, sometimes powered by light instead of electricity, is emerging as a critical piece of AI infrastructure.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/ai-boom-networking-technology-photonics/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baidu ERNIE multimodal AI beats GPT and Gemini in benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/baidu-ernie-multimodal-ai-gpt-and-gemini-benchmarks/</link>
      <description>Baidu’s latest ERNIE model, a super-efficient multimodal AI, is beating GPT and Gemini on key benchmarks and targets enterprise data often ignored by text-focused models. For many businesses, valuable insights are locked in engineering schematics, factory-floor video feeds, medical scans, and logistics dashboards. Baidu’s new model, ERNIE-4.5-VL-28B-A3B-Thinking, is designed to fill this gap. What’s interesting […]
The post Baidu ERNIE multimodal AI beats GPT and Gemini in benchmarks appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:09:44 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/baidu-ernie-multimodal-ai-gpt-and-gemini-benchmarks/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All of My Employees Are AI Agents, and So Are My Executives</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/all-my-employees-are-ai-agents-so-are-my-executives/</link>
      <description>Sam Altman says the one-person billion-dollar company is coming. Maybe I could be that person—if only I could get my colleagues to shut up and stop lying.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/all-my-employees-are-ai-agents-so-are-my-executives/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google reveals its own version of Apple’s AI cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-reveals-its-own-version-of-apple-ai-cloud/</link>
      <description>Google has rolled out Private AI Compute, a new cloud-based processing system designed to bring the privacy of on-device AI to the cloud. The platform aims to give users faster, more capable AI experiences without compromising data security. It combines Google’s most advanced Gemini models with strict privacy safeguards, reflecting the company’s ongoing effort to […]
The post Google reveals its own version of Apple’s AI cloud appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-reveals-its-own-version-of-apple-ai-cloud/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wiz: Security lapses emerge amid the global AI race</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/wiz-security-lapses-emerge-amid-global-ai-race/</link>
      <description>According to Wiz, the race among AI companies is causing many to overlook basic security hygiene practices. 65 percent of the 50 leading AI firms the cybersecurity firm analysed had leaked verified secrets on GitHub. The exposures include API keys, tokens, and sensitive credentials, often buried in code repositories that standard security tools do not […]
The post Wiz: Security lapses emerge amid the global AI race appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:05:25 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/wiz-security-lapses-emerge-amid-global-ai-race/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Former Staffer Calling Out OpenAI’s Erotica Claims</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-big-interview-podcast-steven-adler-openai-erotica/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/the-big-interview-podcast-steven-adler-openai-erotica/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese AI startup Moonshot outperforms GPT-5 and Claude Sonnet 4.5: What you need to know</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/moonshot-ai-gpt-5-claude-comparison-china-breakthrough/</link>
      <description>A Chinese AI startup, Moonshot, has disrupted expectations in artificial intelligence development after its Kimi K2 Thinking model surpassed OpenAI’s GPT-5 and Anthropic’s Claude Sonnet 4.5 across multiple performance benchmarks, sparking renewed debate about whether America’s AI dominance is being challenged by cost-efficient Chinese innovation. Beijing-based Moonshot AI, valued at US$3.3 billion and backed by […]
The post Chinese AI startup Moonshot outperforms GPT-5 and Claude Sonnet 4.5: What you need to know appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/moonshot-ai-gpt-5-claude-comparison-china-breakthrough/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If the US Has to Build Data Centers, Here’s Where They Should Go</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/heres-where-to-build-data-centers-to-keep-emissions-down/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 17:40:27 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/heres-where-to-build-data-centers-to-keep-emissions-down/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alex Karp Goes to War</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/alex-karp-goes-to-war-palantir-big-interview/</link>
      <description>Palantir’s CEO is good with ICE and says he defends human rights. But will Israel and Trump ever go too far for him?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/alex-karp-goes-to-war-palantir-big-interview/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10% of Nvidia’s cost: Why Tesla-Intel chip partnership demands attention</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tesla-intel-chip-partnership-nvidia-cost/</link>
      <description>The potential Tesla-Intel chip partnership could deliver AI chips at just 10% of Nvidia’s cost – a claim that represents a significant development in AI infrastructure that enterprise technology leaders cannot afford to ignore. On November 6, 2025, Tesla CEO Elon Musk stated publicly at the company’s annual shareholder meeting that the electric vehicle manufacturer […]
The post 10% of Nvidia’s cost: Why Tesla-Intel chip partnership demands attention appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 09:13:18 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tesla-intel-chip-partnership-nvidia-cost/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>