<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 09:04:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Can speed and safety truly coexist in the AI race?</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/can-speed-and-safety-truly-coexist-ai-race/</link>
      <description>A criticism about AI safety from an OpenAI researcher aimed at a rival opened a window into the industry’s struggle: a battle against itself. It started with a warning from Boaz Barak, a Harvard professor currently on leave and working on safety at OpenAI. He called the launch of xAI’s Grok model “completely irresponsible,” not […]
The post Can speed and safety truly coexist in the AI race? appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 14:40:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/can-speed-and-safety-truly-coexist-ai-race/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This AI Warps Live Video in Real Time</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/decart-artificial-intelligence-model-live-stream/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 19:49:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/decart-artificial-intelligence-model-live-stream/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roblox’s New Age Verification Feature Uses AI to Scan Teens’ Video Selfies</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/robloxs-new-age-verification-feature-uses-ai-to-scan-teens-video-selfies/</link>
      <description>Roblox will scan video selfies of teens to assess their ages as part of a new Trusted Connections feature that gives users access to unfiltered chatting with people they know.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 19:37:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/robloxs-new-age-verification-feature-uses-ai-to-scan-teens-video-selfies/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mistral AI gives Le Chat voice recognition and deep research tools</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/mistral-ai-le-chat-voice-recognition-deep-research-tools/</link>
      <description>Mistral AI has updated Le Chat with voice recognition, deep research tools, and other features to make the chatbot a more helpful assistant. The company believes that the best AI assistants should help you dive deeper into your thoughts and maintain the flow of conversation. As Mistral AI put it, chatbots are at their best […]
The post Mistral AI gives Le Chat voice recognition and deep research tools appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 15:50:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/mistral-ai-le-chat-voice-recognition-deep-research-tools/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zuckerberg’s $15B bet: How Meta’s ‘Superintelligence Labs’ became Silicon Valley’s most expensive AI talent war</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/meta-superintelligence-ai-lab-zuckerberg-talent-war/</link>
      <description>Mark Zuckerberg has a history of making audacious bets that reshape entire industries – and losing spectacularly when they don’t pan out. After burning through US$46 billion on the metaverse with little to show for it, the Meta CEO is now doubling down with an even more ambitious wager: superintelligence AI.This time, however, the stakes are higher, the competition more fierce, and the potential rewards more transformative than anything Meta has attempted before.With nine-figure compensation packages and infrastructure investments that dwarf even the metaverse spending spree, Zuckerberg’s superintelligence AI gamble represents Silicon Valley’s most expensive talent war – one that could either cement Meta’s position as a tech giant or become another cautionary tale of visionary ambition meeting harsh reality.The birth of Meta Superintelligence LabsThe formation of Meta Superintelligence Labs marks a shift for the social media giant. In an exclusive interview with The Information‘s TITV live-streaming programme, Zuckerberg told founder Jessica Lessin that “the most exciting thing this year is that we’re starting to see early glimpses of self-improvement with the models, which means that developing super intelligence is now in sight.”The vision has driven the company to restructure its entire AI division, with the ambitious goal of delivering what Zuckerberg calls “personal super intelligence to everyone in the world.” The lab’s creation follows a period of internal struggles in Meta’s AI division, including management struggles, employee churn, and product releases that fell flat.Rather than incrementally improving existing systems, Zuckerberg has opted for a complete overhaul, bringing in external leadership and re-imagining the company’s approach to AI development.Are we witnessing the most expensive talent war in tech history?Mark Zuckerberg, Founder, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer/Meta media galleryCentral to Meta’s superintelligence AI ambitions is a talent acquisition strategy that has sent shockwaves through the industry. Zuckerberg has embarked on a spending spree to create the new lab, offering as much as nine-figure pay packages to hire top researchers from companies like OpenAI, Google, Apple and Anthropic.When The Information’s Lessin questi...</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 15:43:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/meta-superintelligence-ai-lab-zuckerberg-talent-war/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackers Are Finding New Ways to Hide Malware in DNS Records</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/dns-records-hidden-malicious-code/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/dns-records-hidden-malicious-code/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Are All the AI Drugs?</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/artificial-intelligence-drug-discovery/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/artificial-intelligence-drug-discovery/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch Our Livestream Replay: Inside the AI Copyright Battles</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/livestream-ai-copyright-battles/</link>
      <description>Curious about generative AI and copyright? On July 16, our writers answered your questions about this critical topic.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 18:32:11 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/livestream-ai-copyright-battles/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump and the Energy Industry Are Eager to Power AI With Fossil Fuels</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/trump-energy-industry-ai-fossil-fuels-pittsburgh-summit/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 16:16:45 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/trump-energy-industry-ai-fossil-fuels-pittsburgh-summit/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Former Top Google Researchers Have Made a New Kind of AI Agent</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/former-top-google-researchers-have-made-a-new-kind-of-ai-agent/</link>
      <description>The mission? Teaching models to better understand how to build code will lead to superintelligent AI.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:02:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/former-top-google-researchers-have-made-a-new-kind-of-ai-agent/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another High-Profile OpenAI Researcher Departs for Meta</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/jason-wei-open-ai-meta/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 02:56:15 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/jason-wei-open-ai-meta/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Tried Grok’s Built-In Anime Companion and It Called Me a Twat</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-xai-ai-companion-ani/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 23:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-xai-ai-companion-ani/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Machines Lab Raises a Record $2 Billion, Announces Cofounders</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/thinking-machines-lab-mira-murati-funding/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 22:02:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/thinking-machines-lab-mira-murati-funding/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Military AI contracts awarded to Anthropic, OpenAI, Google, and xAI</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/military-ai-contracts-awarded-to-anthropic-openai-google-and-xai/</link>
      <description>The Pentagon has opened the military AI floodgates and handed out contracts worth up to $800 million to four of the biggest names: Google, OpenAI, Anthropic, and Elon Musk’s xAI. Each company gets a shot at $200 million worth of work.Dr Doug Matty, Chief Digital and AI Officer, said: “The adoption of AI is transforming the Department’s ability to support our warfighters and maintain strategic advantage over our adversaries.“Leveraging commercially available solutions into an integrated capabilities approach will accelerate the use of advanced AI as part of our joint mission essential tasks in our warfighting domain as well as intelligence, business, and enterprise information systems.” The Pentagon is playing it smart by not putting all their eggs in one basket. Instead of picking a single winner, they’re creating competition among the top players in the hope of ensuring the best AI solutions available for the military and broader government.Just as this announcement dropped, Musk’s xAI rolled out ‘Grok For Government,’ a special version of their AI designed specifically for use by public agencies. This follows similar government initiatives from OpenAI and Anthropic.The new government suite from xAI promises everything from their latest Grok 4 model to ‘Deep Search’ and ‘Tool Use.’ They’re even planning to get security clearances for their engineers and make their AI work in classified environments.The company is clearly trying to position itself as the patriotic choice, talking about “maintaining American leadership in technological innovation” and “turning shovels into tokens”—whatever that means.However, remember when Grok went completely off the rails and started talking about “Mechahitler”? That’s exactly the kind of thing that makes people nervous about using AI for serious government work and even military purposes.When you’re dealing with national security, you can’t have your AI assistant suddenly spouting bizarre alternate histories or making stuff up. The stakes are just too high. It’s like hiring someone to help with important decisions, but sometimes they just start talking nonsense.This whole deal shows just how seriously the government is taking AI—they see it as essential for staying competitive. The partnership with the General Services Ad...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 15:24:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/military-ai-contracts-awarded-to-anthropic-openai-google-and-xai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use AI to start an online business</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-to-use-ai-to-start-an-online-business/</link>
      <description>Nearly every online business now touches artificial intelligence at some point. Research from 2025 shows 78% of companies worldwide use AI for at least one business area. Smaller businesses report higher usage, with 89% saying they use AI each day. Over 280 million businesses worldwide now run at least one AI tool, and many use them for three different functions on average. In the United States, private investment in artificial intelligence reached $109.1 billion for 2025.AI platforms can manage many repetitive or time-consuming parts of building and running a business. Here is how new founders use them:Automating tasks such as billing, emails, and order fulfillmentGenerating product descriptions, marketing content, and blogsProviding support through chatbots and helpdesk systemsHandling customer and sales data, so owners see where to improveTuning online store content for better search engine ranking</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 14:13:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-to-use-ai-to-start-an-online-business/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best four sales PoC tools in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/best-four-sales-poc-tools-in-2025/</link>
      <description>The modern sales landscape is evolving rapidly. Complex buying cycles, high customer expectations, and sophisticated products have made traditional “pitch and close” tactics obsolete. Today, sales professionals must demonstrate tangible value to prospects before closing a deal. This is where proof of concept (PoC) tools take centre stage.A sales PoC is an important bridge between “promise” and “proof.” It allows potential customers to evaluate solutions directly, ensuring they see the value in real-world scenarios. By using advanced PoC tools, sales teams can create immersive experiences, build trust, and accelerate conversion rates.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 09:06:32 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/best-four-sales-poc-tools-in-2025/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FDA’s draft guidance on AI/ML has startups on high alert</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/fdas-draft-guidance-on-ai-ml-has-startups-on-high-alert/</link>
      <description>Author, Eric Elsen, Forte Group.On January 7, 2025, the US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) released draft guidance titled “Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning in Software as a Medical Device”. The document outlines expectations for pre-market applications and lifecycle management of AI-enabled medical software. While the document may have flown under many readers’ radar, the implications for AI-driven diagnostics and early-stage medtech startups are substantial and urgent.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 11:01:44 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/fdas-draft-guidance-on-ai-ml-has-startups-on-high-alert/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>