<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 09:04:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Meta Claims Downloaded Porn at Center of AI Lawsuit Was for ‘Personal Use’</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/meta-claims-downloaded-porn-at-center-of-ai-lawsuit-was-for-personal-use/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:34:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/meta-claims-downloaded-porn-at-center-of-ai-lawsuit-was-for-personal-use/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Man Who Invented AGI</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-man-who-invented-agi/</link>
      <description>Everyone is obsessed with artificial general intelligence—the stage when AI can match all feats of human cognition. The guy who named it saw it as a threat.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:08:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/the-man-who-invented-agi/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How LeapXpert uses AI to bring order and oversight to business messaging</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-leapxpert-uses-ai-to-bring-order-and-oversight-to-business-messaging/</link>
      <description>It’s no longer news that AI is transforming how people communicate at work. The bad (and less common) news, however, is that AI is also making those conversations harder to control. From chat apps to collaboration tools, employees exchange thousands of messages every day, many of which now pass through AI systems that summarise, analyse, or even respond on their behalf. For enterprises, that creates a new kind of exposure: Communication data that is intelligent, unstructured, and often ungoverned.Dima Gutzeit, CEO of business communications platform provider LeapXpert, believes the future of enterprise communication depends on solving this challenge. “AI has made conversation the most valuable dataset inside organisations,” he said. “But without structure and governance, that value quickly turns into risk.”</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:47:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-leapxpert-uses-ai-to-bring-order-and-oversight-to-business-messaging/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Lumana is redefining AI’s role in video surveillance</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-lumana-is-redefining-ais-role-in-video-surveillance/</link>
      <description>For all the progress in artificial intelligence, most video security systems still fail at recognising context in real-world conditions. The majority of cameras can capture real-time footage, but struggle to interpret it. This is a problem turning into a growing concern for smart city designers, manufacturers and schools, each of which may depend on AI to keep people and property safe.Lumana, an AI video surveillance company, believes the fault in these systems lies deep in the foundations of how they are built. “Traditional video platforms were created decades ago to record footage, not interpret it,” said Jordan Shou, Lumana’s Vice President of Marketing. “Adding AI on top of outdated infrastructure is like putting a smart chip in a rotary phone. It might function, but it will never be truly intelligent or reliable enough to understand what’s being captured or help teams make smarter real-time decisions.”</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:36:18 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-lumana-is-redefining-ais-role-in-video-surveillance/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guillermo del Toro Hopes He’s Dead Before AI Art Goes Mainstream</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/guillermo-del-toro-hopes-hes-dead-before-ai-art-goes-mainstream/</link>
      <description>The Frankenstein director tells WIRED the real Victor Frankensteins are tyrannical politicians and Silicon Valley tech bros.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/guillermo-del-toro-hopes-hes-dead-before-ai-art-goes-mainstream/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WIRED Roundup: AI Psychosis, Missing FTC Files, and Google Bedbugs</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-wired-roundup-ai-psychosis-ftc-files-google-bedbugs/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:27:08 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-wired-roundup-ai-psychosis-ftc-files-google-bedbugs/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bending Spoons’ acquisition of AOL shows the value of legacy platforms</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/bending-spoons-acquisition-of-aol-shows-the-value-of-legacy-platforms/</link>
      <description>The acquisition of a legacy platform like AOL by Bending Spoons shows the latent value of long-standing digital ecosystems. AOL’s 30 million monthly active users represent an enduring brand and a data-rich resource that can be used in AI-driven services. That statement is true only if the data is properly governed and integrated. Such deals […]
The post Bending Spoons’ acquisition of AOL shows the value of legacy platforms appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:19:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/bending-spoons-acquisition-of-aol-shows-the-value-of-legacy-platforms/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand becomes one of the first in Asia to get the Sora app</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/thailand-becomes-one-of-the-first-in-asia-to-get-the-sora-app/</link>
      <description>Citizens of Thailand can now access the Sora app, giving local creators an early look at OpenAI’s new AI video tool in Asia. Thailand already has an active creative scene, and this launch is meant to support more visual storytelling from the region. The app’s rollout also includes Vietnam and Taiwan. Sora first arrived in […]
The post Thailand becomes one of the first in Asia to get the Sora app appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/thailand-becomes-one-of-the-first-in-asia-to-get-the-sora-app/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Samsung’s semiconductor recovery: How AI demand reversed four quarters of decline</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/samsung-semiconductor-recovery-q3-2025/</link>
      <description>Samsung’s semiconductor recovery has materialised during the third quarter of 2025, with the South Korean tech giant posting an operating profit of KRW 12.2 trillion (US$8.6 billion) – more than double the previous quarter and ending a streak of four consecutive quarterly declines in its chip division. The turnaround centred on Samsung’s Device Solutions division, […]
The post Inside Samsung’s semiconductor recovery: How AI demand reversed four quarters of decline appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/samsung-semiconductor-recovery-q3-2025/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reco wants to eliminate the blind spot of shadow AI</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/reco-wants-to-eliminate-the-blind-spot-of-shadow-ai/</link>
      <description>AI is spreading through workplaces faster than any other technology in recent memory. Every day, employees connect AI technologies to enterprise systems, often without permission or oversight from IT security teams. The result is what experts call shadow AI – a growing web of tools and integrations that access company data unmonitored.Dr.Tal Shapira, Co founder and CTO at SaaS security and AI governance solution provider Reco, says this invisible sprawl could become one of the biggest threats facing organisations today, especially since the current speed of AI adoption has outpaced enterprise safeguards.“We went from ‘AI is coming’ to ‘AI is everywhere’ in about 18 months. The problem is that governance frameworks simply haven’t caught up,” Shapira said.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 02:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/reco-wants-to-eliminate-the-blind-spot-of-shadow-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta, Google, and Microsoft Triple Down on AI Spending</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/microsoft-google-meta-2025-earnings/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 02:09:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/microsoft-google-meta-2025-earnings/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Agents Are Terrible Freelance Workers</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/ai-agents-are-terrible-freelance-workers/</link>
      <description>A new benchmark measures how well AI agents can automate economically valuable chores. Human-level AI is still some ways off.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/ai-agents-are-terrible-freelance-workers/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cursor 2.0 pivots to multi-agent AI coding, debuts Composer model</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/cursor-2-pivots-multi-agent-ai-coding-debuts-composer-model/</link>
      <description>Cursor has released its latest AI software development platform with a new multi-agent interface and the debut of its coding model, Composer.The new Composer model is described as a “frontier model”. Cursor claims it is four times faster than other models of similar intelligence. The company built it specifically for “low-latency agentic coding” within the Cursor environment. The company states that the model can complete most conversational turns in under 30 seconds.This speed is intended to improve the developer’s workflow. Early testers reported that the ability to iterate quickly with the model was a key benefit. They also apparently grew to trust Composer for handling complex and multi-step coding tasks.To achieve this performance, Composer was trained with a suite of powerful tools. One of the key tools mentioned is “codebase-wide semantic search”. This training, Cursor says, makes Composer much better at understanding and working in large, complex codebases—a common challenge for many generative AI coding assistants.The second major update is the new user interface. Upon opening the new version, users will notice a “more focused” design. The entire AI-driven software development experience in Cursor has been rebuilt to be “centered around agents rather than files”. This change in focus is designed to allow developers to concentrate on their desired outcomes, while the AI agents manage the underlying details and code implementation.For developers who still need to work directly with the code, the new layout retains the ability to open files easily. Users can also revert to the “classic IDE” view if they prefer.A core feature of Cursor’s new platform is its ability to run many AI agents in parallel without them interfering with one another. This functionality is powered by technologies like “git worktrees or remote machines”.Cursor also noted an interesting emergent strategy from this parallel approach. They found that assigning the same problem to multiple different models and then selecting the best solution “greatly improves the final output”. This is particularly effective for more difficult or complex tasks.The company acknowledges that as AI agents take on more of the coding workload, new bottlenecks have emerged for developers. The two biggest n...</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:46:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/cursor-2-pivots-multi-agent-ai-coding-debuts-composer-model/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extropic Aims to Disrupt the Data Center Bonanza</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/extropic-aims-to-disrupt-the-data-center-bonanza/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:11:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/extropic-aims-to-disrupt-the-data-center-bonanza/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump Is the First AI Slop President</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/donald-trump-ai-slop-white-house/</link>
      <description>How do AI videos end up on Donald Trump’s social media accounts? WIRED investigates.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/donald-trump-ai-slop-white-house/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrating AI from Nvidia to Huawei: Opportunities and trade-offs</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/migrating-ai-from-nvidia-to-huawei-opportunities-and-trade-offs/</link>
      <description>For many years, Nvidia has been the de facto leader in AI model training and inference infrastructure, thanks to its mature GPU range, the CUDA software stack, and a huge developer community. Moving away from that base is therefore a strategic and tactical consideration.Huawei AI represents an alternative to Nvidia, with the Chinese company signalling an increasingly aggressive move into AI hardware, chips, and systems. This presents decision-makers with opportunities. For example:The company has unveiled its SuperPod clusters that link thousands of Ascend NPUs, with claims that data links, for example, are “62× quicker”, and that the offering is more advanced than Nvidia’s next-gen alternative.Huawei’s strategy emphasises its inference advantages.In domestic or alternative markets where export control or supply-chain risk makes a single-vendor (Nvidia) strategy less robust, the Chinese company’s portfolio is the logical choice.Any migration to a Huawei-centred pipeline isn’t, however a simple a plug-in replacement. It would entail a shift in developer ecosystem and possible regional re-alignment.Business advantages of moving to a Huawei AI-centred pipelineWhen contemplating the shift, several business advantages may drive a final decision. Relying on one major vendor (namely, Nvidia) can incur risks: pricing leverage, export controls, supply shortages, or a single point of failure in innovation. Adopting or migrating to Huawei has the potential to provide negotiation leverage, avoid vendor lock-in, and offer access to alternate supply chains. That’s especially relevant in areas where Nvidia faces export restrictions.If an organisation operates in a region where Huawei’s ecosystem is stronger (e.g., China, parts of Asia) or where domestic incentives favour local hardware, shifting to Huawei could align with corporate strategy. For instance, ByteDance has begun training a new model primarily on Huawei’s Ascend 910B chips with notable success.Huawei’s technology focuses on inference and large-scale deployments, and thus may be better suited to long-term use, rather than occasional use of large infrastructures for training, followed by less intensive inference. If an organisation’s workloads are inference-heavy, a Huawei stack may offer advantages in cost and ...</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/migrating-ai-from-nvidia-to-huawei-opportunities-and-trade-offs/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Adobe’s Corrective AI Can Change the Emotions of a Voice-Over</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/adobe-max-sneaks-2025-corrective-ai/</link>
      <description>Ahead of Adobe’s MAX Sneaks event, WIRED got an exclusive look at a new tool that can change the tone and style of a voice-over.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/adobe-max-sneaks-2025-corrective-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counterintuitive’s new chip aims escape the AI ‘twin trap’</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-twin-trap-next-generation-chip-and-software/</link>
      <description>AI startup company, Counterintuitive, has set out to build “reasoning-native computing,” enabling machines to understand rather than simply mimic. Such a breakthrough has the potential to shift AI from pattern recognition to genuine comprehension, paving the way for systems that can think and make decisions – in other words, to be more “human-like.” Counterintuitive Chairman, […]
The post Counterintuitive’s new chip aims escape the AI ‘twin trap’ appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:22:06 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-twin-trap-next-generation-chip-and-software/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Director of a Raunchy 3-Hour Dracula Movie Says AI Is Gross and Slimy. That’s Why He Used It</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-director-of-a-raunchy-3-hour-dracula-movie-says-ai-is-gross-and-slimy-thats-why-he-used-it/</link>
      <description>Radu Jude’s AI-filled adaptation features Dracula doing porn and exploiting tech workers.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/the-director-of-a-raunchy-3-hour-dracula-movie-says-ai-is-gross-and-slimy-thats-why-he-used-it/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI unveils open-weight AI safety models for developers</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-unveils-open-weight-ai-safety-models-for-developers/</link>
      <description>OpenAI is putting more safety controls directly into the hands of AI developers with a new research preview of “safeguard” models. The new ‘gpt-oss-safeguard’ family of open-weight models is aimed squarely at customising content classification. The new offering will include two models, gpt-oss-safeguard-120b and a smaller gpt-oss-safeguard-20b. Both are fine-tuned versions of the existing gpt-oss […]
The post OpenAI unveils open-weight AI safety models for developers appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 09:31:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-unveils-open-weight-ai-safety-models-for-developers/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI restructures, enters ‘next chapter’ of Microsoft partnership</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-restructures-next-chapter-microsoft-partnership/</link>
      <description>OpenAI has completed a major reorganisation and, in the same breath, signed a new definitive partnership agreement with Microsoft. Starting with OpenAI’s reorganisation, the aim is to solidify the nonprofit’s control over the for-profit business and establish the newly named OpenAI Foundation as a global philanthropic powerhouse, holding equity in the commercial arm valued at […]
The post OpenAI restructures, enters ‘next chapter’ of Microsoft partnership appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 13:43:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-restructures-next-chapter-microsoft-partnership/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI’s bold India play: Free ChatGPT Go access</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-chatgpt-go-free-india-market-strategy/</link>
      <description>OpenAI just made its biggest bet on India yet. Starting November 4, the company will hand out free year-long access to ChatGPT Go — a move that puts every marketing executive on notice about how aggressively AI companies are fighting for the world’s fastest-growing digital market. OpenAI will offer its ChatGPT Go plan to users […]
The post OpenAI’s bold India play: Free ChatGPT Go access appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:01:27 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-chatgpt-go-free-india-market-strategy/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>