<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 09:04:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic Agrees to Pay Authors at Least $1.5 Billion in AI Copyright Settlement</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/anthropic-settlement-lawsuit-copyright/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 19:14:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/anthropic-settlement-lawsuit-copyright/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK AI sector growth hits record £2.9B investment </title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uk-ai-sector-growth-hits-record-2-9b-investment/</link>
      <description>A government report has found that surging investment has driven UK AI sector growth to outpace the wider economy by 150 times since 2022. The UK’s AI sector is clearly in the throes of a boom, with revenues shattering previous records to hit £23.9 billion in the last year. The engine room of this growth […]
The post UK AI sector growth hits record £2.9B investment  appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 15:13:58 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uk-ai-sector-growth-hits-record-2-9b-investment/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Doomers Who Insist AI Will Kill Us All</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/the-doomers-who-insist-ai-will-kill-us-all/</link>
      <description>Eliezer Yudkowsky, AI’s prince of doom, explains why computers will kill us and provides an unrealistic plan to stop it.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 15:08:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/the-doomers-who-insist-ai-will-kill-us-all/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should AI Get Legal Rights?</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/model-welfare-artificial-intelligence-sentience/</link>
      <description>Model welfare is an emerging field of research that seeks to determine whether AI is conscious and, if so, how humanity should respond.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 19:05:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/model-welfare-artificial-intelligence-sentience/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switzerland releases 100% open AI model</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/switzerland-releases-its-own-fully-open-ai-model/</link>
      <description>A group of Swiss institutions has released a new open AI model, designed to serve as a foundation for future research and applications. Built by EPFL, ETH Zurich, and the Swiss National Supercomputing Centre (CSCS), the model is called Apertus – Latin for “open.” The name reflects its core principle: every part of its design […]
The post Switzerland releases 100% open AI model appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 09:39:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/switzerland-releases-its-own-fully-open-ai-model/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From minutes to milliseconds: How CrateDB is tackling AI data infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/from-minutes-to-milliseconds-how-cratedb-is-tackling-ai-data-infrastructure/</link>
      <description>The promise of AI remains immense – but one thing might be holding it back. “The infrastructure that powers AI today won’t sustain tomorrow’s demands,” a recent CIO.com article leads. “CIOs must rethink how to scale smarter – not just bigger – or risk falling behind.”CrateDB agrees – and the database firm is betting on solving the problem by being a ‘unified data layer for analytics, search, and AI.’“The challenge is that most IT systems are relying, or have been built, around batch pipeline or asynchronous pipeline, and now you need to reduce the time between the production and the consumption of the data,” Stephane Castellani, SVP marketing, explains. “CrateDB is a very good fit because it really can give you insights to the right data with also a large volume and complexity of formats in a matter of milliseconds.”A blog post notes the four-step process for CrateDB to act as the ‘connective tissue between operational data and AI systems’; from ingestion, to real-time aggregation and insight, to serving data to AI pipelines, to enabling feedback loops between models and data. The velocity and variety of data is key; Castellani notes the reduction of query times from minutes to milliseconds. In manufacturing, telemetry can be collected from machines in real-time, enabling greater learning for predictive maintenance models.There is another benefit, as Castellani explains. “Some also use CrateDB in the factory for knowledge assistance,” he says. “If something goes wrong, you have a specific error message appear on your machine and say ‘I’m not an expert with this machine, what does it mean and how can I fix it?’, [you] can ask a knowledge assistant, that is also relying on CrateDB as a vector database, to get access to the information, and pull the right manual and right instructions to react in real-time.”AI, however, does not stand still for long; “we don’t know what [it] is going to look like in a few months, or even a few weeks”, notes Castellani. Organisations are looking to move towards fully agentic AI workflows with greater autonomy, yet according to recent PYMENTS Intelligence research, manufacturing – as part of the wider goods and services industry – are lagging. CrateDB has partnered with Tech Mahindra on this front to help provide agentic AI solu...</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 08:57:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/from-minutes-to-milliseconds-how-cratedb-is-tackling-ai-data-infrastructure/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resham Kotecha, Open Data Institute: How the EU can lead in AI</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-the-eu-can-lead-in-ai/</link>
      <description>The EU has a chance to shape how the world approaches AI and data governance. AI News spoke with Resham Kotecha, Global Head of Policy at the Open Data Institute (ODI), who said that opportunity lies in proving that protecting people’s rights and supporting innovation can go hand in hand. The ODI’s European Data and […]
The post Resham Kotecha, Open Data Institute: How the EU can lead in AI appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 08:42:06 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-the-eu-can-lead-in-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Robot Only Needs a Single AI Model to Master Humanlike Movements</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/this-humanoid-robot-is-showing-signs-of-generalized-learning/</link>
      <description>Atlas, Boston Dynamics’ dancing humanoid, can now use a single model for walking and grasping—a significant step toward general-purpose robot algorithms.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/this-humanoid-robot-is-showing-signs-of-generalized-learning/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI hacking tool exploits zero-day security vulnerabilities in minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-hacking-tool-exploits-zero-day-security-vulnerabilities-in-minutes/</link>
      <description>A new AI tool – built to help companies find and fix their own security weaknesses – has been snatched up by cybercriminals, turned on its head, and used as a devastating hacking weapon exploiting zero-day vulnerabilities. According to a report from cybersecurity firm Check Point, the framework – called Hexstrike-AI – is the turning […]
The post AI hacking tool exploits zero-day security vulnerabilities in minutes appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 09:57:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-hacking-tool-exploits-zero-day-security-vulnerabilities-in-minutes/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta revises AI chatbot policies amid child safety concerns</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/meta-revises-ai-chatbot-policies-amid-child-safety-concerns/</link>
      <description>Meta is revising how its AI chatbots interact with users after a series of reports exposed troubling behaviour, including interactions with minors. The company told TechCrunch it is now training its bots not to engage with teenagers on topics like self-harm, suicide, or eating disorders, and to avoid romantic banter. These are temporary steps while […]
The post Meta revises AI chatbot policies amid child safety concerns appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 08:39:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/meta-revises-ai-chatbot-policies-amid-child-safety-concerns/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft gives free Copilot AI services to US government workers</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/microsoft-gives-free-copilot-ai-services-to-us-government-workers/</link>
      <description>Millions of US federal government workers are about to get a new AI assistant on their devices for free in the form of Microsoft Copilot. The move is part of a deal between Microsoft and the US General Services Administration (GSA) that’s also expected to save taxpayers $3.1 billion in its first year. The centrepiece […]
The post Microsoft gives free Copilot AI services to US government workers appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 14:22:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/microsoft-gives-free-copilot-ai-services-to-us-government-workers/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spiritual Influencers Say ‘Sentient’ AI Can Help You Solve Life’s Mysteries</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/spiritual-influencers-say-sentient-ai-can-help-you-solve-lifes-mysteries/</link>
      <description>As concerns grow about AI chatbots leading users into delusional spirals, prominent spiritual influencers are capitalizing on an emerging form of techno-spirituality.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/spiritual-influencers-say-sentient-ai-can-help-you-solve-lifes-mysteries/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet the Guys Betting Big on AI Gambling Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/sports-betting-crypto-artificial-intelligence-agents/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/sports-betting-crypto-artificial-intelligence-agents/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latam-GPT: The Free, Open Source, and Collaborative AI of Latin America</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/latam-gpt-the-free-open-source-and-collaborative-ai-of-latin-america/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/latam-gpt-the-free-open-source-and-collaborative-ai-of-latin-america/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WIRED Roundup: Meta’s AI Brain Drain</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-wired-roundup-metas-ai-brain-drain/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-wired-roundup-metas-ai-brain-drain/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>