<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:04:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>I Wasn’t Sure I Wanted Anthropic to Pay Me for My Books—I Do Now</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/anthropic-settlement-books-copyright/</link>
      <description>Anthropic agreed to a $1.5 billion settlement for authors whose books were used to train its AI model. As an author who fits that description, I’ve come around to the idea.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/anthropic-settlement-books-copyright/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware nods to AI but looks to long-term</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/broadcom-nods-at-ai-looks-to-long-term/</link>
      <description>Owner of VMware, Broadcom, announced that its VMware Cloud Foundation platform is now AI native at the VMware Explore conference a few weeks ago. It was the latest move by the company to keep up to speed with the rest of the technology industry’s wide and rapid adoption of large language models, yet came as […]
The post VMware nods to AI but looks to long-term appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 15:44:08 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/broadcom-nods-at-ai-looks-to-long-term/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yext Scout Guides Brands Through AI Search Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/yext-scout-guides-brands-through-ai-search-challenges/</link>
      <description>Customers are discovering brands and learning about products and services in new ways from traditional search to AI search, to AI agents and more, the discovery journey has completely changed, and brands need to adapt to the new paradigm.Launched earlier this year, Yext Scout is an AI search and competitive intelligence agent that’s designed to boost brand visibility and uncover critical insights related to the new AI-driven search platforms, alongside ‘traditional’ searches as we know them.Scout is part of Yext, the leading brand visibility platform. Scout provides performance benchmarks laid out against a brand’s local competitors, and creates smart recommendations that you can act on, in real-time.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:19:15 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/yext-scout-guides-brands-through-ai-search-challenges/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft’s AI Chief Says Machine Consciousness Is an ‘Illusion’</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/microsofts-ai-chief-says-machine-consciousness-is-an-illusion/</link>
      <description>Mustafa Suleyman says that designing AI systems to exceed human intelligence—and to mimic behavior that suggests consciousness—would be “dangerous and misguided.”</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 18:04:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/microsofts-ai-chief-says-machine-consciousness-is-an-illusion/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Melania Trump’s AI Era Is Upon Us</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/melania-trumps-ai-era-is-upon-us/</link>
      <description>The ever elusive first lady has emerged with a brief to exert thought leadership over AI, for the children. Some insiders are excited; others won&#x27;t touch the subject with a 10-foot pole.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/melania-trumps-ai-era-is-upon-us/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join Us for WIRED’s AI Power Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/wired-ai-power-summit/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/wired-ai-power-summit/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Man vs. Machine Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/san-francisco-hackathon-man-vs-machine/</link>
      <description>At a weekend hackathon in San Francisco, more than 100 coders gathered to test whether they could beat AI—and win a $12,500 cash prize.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/san-francisco-hackathon-man-vs-machine/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is AI the New Frontier of Women’s Oppression?</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/is-ai-the-new-frontier-of-female-oppression/</link>
      <description>In her new book, feminist author Laura Bates explores how sexbots, AI assistants, and deepfakes are reinventing misogyny and harming women.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:56:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/is-ai-the-new-frontier-of-female-oppression/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Arab Emirates Releases a Tiny But Powerful AI Model</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/uae-releases-a-tiny-but-powerful-reasoning-model/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 12:33:44 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/uae-releases-a-tiny-but-powerful-reasoning-model/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Machines becomes OpenAI’s first services partner in APAC</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/thinking-machines-becomes-openai-first-services-partner-in-apac/</link>
      <description>Thinking Machines Data Science is joining forces with OpenAI to help more businesses across Asia Pacific turn artificial intelligence into measurable results. The collaboration makes Thinking Machines the first official Services Partner for OpenAI in the region. The partnership comes as AI adoption in APAC continues to rise. An IBM study found that 61% of […]
The post Thinking Machines becomes OpenAI’s first services partner in APAC appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 10:16:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/thinking-machines-becomes-openai-first-services-partner-in-apac/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alibaba’s new Qwen model to supercharge AI transcription tools</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/alibaba-new-qwen-model-supercharge-ai-transcription-tools/</link>
      <description>AI speech transcription tools are about to get a lot more competitive with Alibaba’s Qwen team pulling unveiling the Qwen3-ASR-Flash model. Built upon the powerful Qwen3-Omni intelligence and trained using a massive dataset with tens of millions of hours of speech data, this isn’t just another AI speech recognition model. The team says it’s designed […]
The post Alibaba’s new Qwen model to supercharge AI transcription tools appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 16:33:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/alibaba-new-qwen-model-supercharge-ai-transcription-tools/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Siddhartha Choudhury, Booking.com: Fighting online fraud with AI</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/siddhartha-choudhury-booking-com-fighting-online-fraud-with-ai/</link>
      <description>AI News caught up with Siddhartha Choudhury, a Senior Product Manager at Booking.com, to get the inside scoop on how the technology is keeping your bookings – and data – safe from security threats like online fraud. When you book a holiday online, you’re placing a lot of trust in a website. You trust it […]
The post Siddhartha Choudhury, Booking.com: Fighting online fraud with AI appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 12:54:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/siddhartha-choudhury-booking-com-fighting-online-fraud-with-ai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Hate My AI Friend</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/i-hate-my-ai-friend/</link>
      <description>The chatbot-enabled Friend necklace eavesdrops on your life and provides a running commentary that’s snarky and unhelpful. Worse, it can also make the people around you uneasy.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/i-hate-my-ai-friend/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psychological Tricks Can Get AI to Break the Rules</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/psychological-tricks-can-get-ai-to-break-the-rules/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/psychological-tricks-can-get-ai-to-break-the-rules/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE Has Spyware Now</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/ice-has-spyware-now/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/ice-has-spyware-now/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>