<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 09:04:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI&#x27;s Sora Loses Its Top App Store Ranking to Dave&#x27;s Hot Chicken</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/sora-app-store-daves-hot-chicken/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 19:30:26 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/sora-app-store-daves-hot-chicken/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI connects ChatGPT to enterprise data to surface knowledge</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-connects-chatgpt-enterprise-data-surface-knowledge/</link>
      <description>OpenAI is surfacing company knowledge by connecting ChatGPT to enterprise data, turning it from a general assistant into a custom analyst. For business leaders, generative AI’s potential has always been limited by its lack of access to internal data. Even the best AI isn’t helpful if it can’t access the info needed to do a […]
The post OpenAI connects ChatGPT to enterprise data to surface knowledge appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:50:05 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-connects-chatgpt-enterprise-data-surface-knowledge/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Data Centers Actually Work</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-how-data-centers-actually-work/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-how-data-centers-actually-work/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic’s billion-dollar TPU expansion signals a strategic shift in enterprise AI infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/anthropic-tpu-expansion-enterprise-ai-infrastructure/</link>
      <description>Anthropic’s announcement this week that it will deploy up to one million Google Cloud TPUs in a deal worth tens of billions of dollars marks a significant recalibration in enterprise AI infrastructure strategy.  The expansion, expected to bring over a gigawatt of capacity online in 2026, represents one of the largest single commitments to specialised […]
The post Anthropic’s billion-dollar TPU expansion signals a strategic shift in enterprise AI infrastructure appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/anthropic-tpu-expansion-enterprise-ai-infrastructure/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open-source AI video from Lightricks offers 4K, sound, and faster rendering</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/open-source-ai-video-from-lightricks-offers-4k-sound-and-faster-rendering/</link>
      <description>Lightricks is upping the ante for rapid video creation and iteration with its latest artificial intelligence model. The company claims its newly released LTX-2 foundation model can generate new content faster than playback speed, plus it raises the bar in resolution and quality.The open-source LTX-2 can generate a stylised, high-definition, six-second video in just five seconds without no compromise in quality, enabling creators to pump out professional content much faster than previously.It’s an impressive achievement, but it’s not the only parameter that sets LTX-2 apart from others. It combines native audio and video synthesis with open-source transparency, and if users are willing to wait just a few seconds longer, they can enhance their outputs to 4K resolution at up to 48 frames per second, the company says. Even better, creators can run the software on consumer-grade GPUs, dramatically reducing their compute costs.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/open-source-ai-video-from-lightricks-offers-4k-sound-and-faster-rendering/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomy in the real world? Druid AI unveils AI agent ‘factory’</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/druid-ai-agentic-factory-automation-in-the-real-world/</link>
      <description>At its London Symbiosis 4 event on 22 October, Druid AI introduced what it terms Virtual Authoring Teams – a new generation of AI agents that can design, test, and deploy other AI agents. The announcement marks a move towards what the company calls a ‘factory model’ for AI automation. According to Druid, the system […]
The post Autonomy in the real world? Druid AI unveils AI agent ‘factory’ appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:46:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/druid-ai-agentic-factory-automation-in-the-real-world/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Man Who Makes AI Slop by Hand</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/made-in-china-the-chinese-creator-who-imitates-ai-slop/</link>
      <description>Chinese creator Tianran Mu went viral for mimicking the eerie, unsettling aesthetic of AI videos, but his work is 100 percent human.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/made-in-china-the-chinese-creator-who-imitates-ai-slop/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do AI ‘humanisers’ compare to human editing?</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-do-ai-humanisers-compare-to-human-editing/</link>
      <description>The emergence of artificial intelligence has fundamentally altered the field of content creation. Tools capable of generating coherent, often impressive, text, are now ubiquitous. Yet, despite their sophistication, AI-generated content presents a persistent challenge because it often has a “robotic” quality, lacking the warmth, nuance, and genuine voice that connects with a human audience. The digital coldness necessitates an important step: humanisation.This need has given rise to specialised AI humaniser tools designed to inject naturalness into machine prose. Simultaneously, the age-old craft of human editing continues to refine and elevate text. This brings us to a pivotal question for anyone producing written content today. When transforming raw AI output into compelling prose, is it better to use an AI humaniser or rely on the irreplaceable touch of a human editor?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:14:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-do-ai-humanisers-compare-to-human-editing/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI data residency advances enterprise AI governance</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-data-residency-advances-enterprise-ai-governance/</link>
      <description>For chief data and information officers, especially in tightly regulated sectors, data governance has been a major cause preventing enterprise adoption of AI models. The issue of data sovereignty – which concerns where company data is handled and kept – has held many back, forcing them to use complex private cloud solutions. Others have simply […]
The post OpenAI data residency advances enterprise AI governance appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:07:27 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-data-residency-advances-enterprise-ai-governance/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT’s Horny Era Could Be Its Stickiest Yet</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/chatgpt-horny-era/</link>
      <description>OpenAI will soon let adults create erotic content in ChatGPT. Experts say that could lead to “emotional commodification,” or horniness as a revenue stream.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/chatgpt-horny-era/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta hires and fires AI workers: Behind the contradiction</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/meta-ai-job-cuts-hiring-contradiction-2025/</link>
      <description>Reports are circulating this week that Meta is cutting approximately 600 positions from its AI division, a move that seems paradoxical given the company’s aggressive recruitment campaign over recent months. The contradiction raises important questions about Meta’s AI strategy and what it signals for the broader tech industry. For those following Meta AI job cuts, […]
The post Meta hires and fires AI workers: Behind the contradiction appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 09:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/meta-ai-job-cuts-hiring-contradiction-2025/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Models Get Brain Rot, Too</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/ai-models-social-media-cognitive-decline-study/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/ai-models-social-media-cognitive-decline-study/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Open Source Robot Brain Thinks in 3D</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/this-open-source-robot-brain-thinks-in-3d/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:00:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/this-open-source-robot-brain-thinks-in-3d/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCP prompt hijacking: Examining the major AI security threat</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/mcp-prompt-hijacking-examining-major-ai-security-threat/</link>
      <description>Security experts at JFrog have found a ‘prompt hijacking’ threat that exploits weak spots in how AI systems talk to each other using MCP (Model Context Protocol). Business leaders want to make AI more helpful by directly using company data and tools. But, hooking AI up like this also opens up new security risks, not […]
The post MCP prompt hijacking: Examining the major AI security threat appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:57:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/mcp-prompt-hijacking-examining-major-ai-security-threat/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People Who Say They’re Experiencing AI Psychosis Beg the FTC for Help</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/ftc-complaints-chatgpt-ai-psychosis/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/ftc-complaints-chatgpt-ai-psychosis/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI is changing how we build links for SEO</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-is-changing-how-we-build-links-for-seo/</link>
      <description>Link strategies are important in improving search engine optimisation (SEO) and online visibility. Artificial intelligence is changing these strategies, making them more accurate and efficient. This article examines AI’s impact on link strategies, highlighting current tools and future trends. Businesses are always looking for new ways to improve their online presence. Link strategies are the […]
The post AI is changing how we build links for SEO appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 08:18:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-is-changing-how-we-build-links-for-seo/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI’s Atlas Browser Takes Direct Aim at Google Chrome</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-atlas-browser-chrome-agents-web-browsing/</link>
      <description>The new ChatGPT-powered web browser is OpenAI’s boldest play yet to reinvent how people use the web.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:06:41 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-atlas-browser-chrome-agents-web-browsing/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forget SEO. Welcome to the World of Generative Engine Optimization</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/goodbye-seo-hello-geo-brandlight-openai/</link>
      <description>This holiday season, more shoppers are expected to use chatbots to figure out what to buy. ‘Tis the season for GEO.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/goodbye-seo-hello-geo-brandlight-openai/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI adoption is moving IT operations from reactive to proactive</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-ai-adoption-it-operations-reactive-to-proactive/</link>
      <description>CIOs want to fix IT problems faster without expanding headcount, and many see AI adoption as the solution for their operations. For ages, they’ve used things like automation and self-help portals to handle this, so their teams can solve issues quickly. Now, AI is getting involved, and lots of companies are trying to use it […]
The post How AI adoption is moving IT operations from reactive to proactive appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:59:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-ai-adoption-it-operations-reactive-to-proactive/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Businesses still face the AI data challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/businesses-still-face-the-ai-data-challenge/</link>
      <description>A few years ago, the business technology world’s favourite buzzword was ‘Big Data’ – a reference to organisations’ mass collection of information that could be used to suggest previously unexplored ways of operating, and float ideas about what strategies they may best pursue. What’s becoming increasingly apparent is that the problems companies faced in using […]
The post Businesses still face the AI data challenge appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:55:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/businesses-still-face-the-ai-data-challenge/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How accounting firms are using AI agents to reclaim time and trust</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/finance-ai-reclaiming-time-trust-with-openai-chatgpt/</link>
      <description>For CFOs and CIOs under pressure to modernise finance operations, automation – as seen in several generations of RPA (robotic process automation) – isn’t enough. It’s apparent that transparency and explainability matter just as much. Accounting firms and finance functions inside organisations are now turning to AI systems that reason, not just compute. One of […]
The post How accounting firms are using AI agents to reclaim time and trust appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 11:41:15 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/finance-ai-reclaiming-time-trust-with-openai-chatgpt/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The FTC Is Disappearing Blog Posts About AI Published During Lina Khan’s Tenure</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/ftc-removes-blog-posts-about-ai-authored-by-by-lina-khan/</link>
      <description>Save StorySave this story</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/ftc-removes-blog-posts-about-ai-authored-by-by-lina-khan/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>