<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Notícias de Inteligência Artificial (EN)</title>
    <link>https://github.com/rafaelamiranda/noticias-ia</link>
    <description>
Principais notícias relacionadas a inteligência artificial
dos últimos 7 dias, em Inglês.
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 09:04:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>UK and Singapore form alliance to guide AI in finance</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uk-and-singapore-form-alliance-guide-ai-in-finance/</link>
      <description>The UK and Singapore are laying the groundwork for what might become a blueprint for international AI cooperation in finance. For their tenth annual Financial Dialogue, representatives from the UK’s Financial Conduct Authority and Singapore’s Monetary Authority met in London earlier this week alongside fintech companies from both nations showing off their latest AI solutions. […]
The post UK and Singapore form alliance to guide AI in finance appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 12:44:51 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uk-and-singapore-form-alliance-guide-ai-in-finance/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI rejects Robinhood’s unauthorised tokenised shares</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-rejects-robinhood-unauthorised-tokenised-shares/</link>
      <description>Robinhood has begun offering tokenised shares in private companies, sparking backlash from OpenAI as one of the targeted firms. During an event in Cannes on Monday, Robinhood co-founder and CEO Vlad Tenev displayed what he described as “stock tokens” for OpenAI and SpaceX. The move forms part of Robinhood’s European expansion, which also includes offering […]
The post OpenAI rejects Robinhood’s unauthorised tokenised shares appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 15:54:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-rejects-robinhood-unauthorised-tokenised-shares/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Sensual Butt Songs to Santa’s Alleged Coke Habit: AI Slop Music Is Getting Harder to Avoid</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/from-sensual-butt-songs-to-santas-alleged-coke-habit-ai-slop-music-is-getting-harder-to-avoid/</link>
      <description>Even listeners who hate the idea of AI music are getting served tracks like “Taste My Ass” and “I Caught Santa Claus Sniffing Cocaine” on Spotify and other streamers.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 12:55:11 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/from-sensual-butt-songs-to-santas-alleged-coke-habit-ai-slop-music-is-getting-harder-to-avoid/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyXcel research discovers a third of UK businesses at AI risk</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/cyxcel-research-discovers-a-third-of-uk-businesses-at-ai-risk/</link>
      <description>Research by cybersecurity consultancy CyXcel has revealed 29% of UK businesses surveyed have only recently implemented their first AI risk strategy, with 31% not no AI governance policies set up. The is despite a third of businesses recognising AI as a potential cybersecurity threat. The blind spot in AI risk preparedness leaves businesses prey to data leaks and breaches, operational disruptions, and regulatory fines, the company says.Of those surveyed, 18% of UK and US organisations are unprepared for AI data poisoning, a form of cyberattack that targets the training data of AI and machine learning models. Moreover, 16% have no policies in place to fight cloning and deepfake incidents.Megha Kumar, Chief Product Officer and Head of Geopolitical Risk at CyXcel, stated there is a catch 22 situation, where companies want to adopt AI solutions but simultaneously worry about its risks. “Organisations want to use AI but are worried about risks – especially as many do not have a policy and governance process in place.”He said CyXcel’s Digital Risk Management (DRM) platform can help respond to mounting threats. “The CyXcel DRM provides clients in all sectors, especially those that have limited technological resources in house, with a robust tool to proactively manage digital risk and harness AI confidently and safely.”The CyXcel DRM platform is designed to provide businesses with insight into growing AI risks. It combines cyber, legal, technical, and strategic expertise to help manage threats and improve digital resilience. The company says its DRM platform also helps implement governance and policies that will mitigate possible risks.The DRM platform provides strategies for – AI, Cyber, Supply Chain, Geopolitics, Regulation, Technology (OT/IT), and Corporate Responsibility, available through a dashboard where users can manage digitals risks using solutions proffered by the platform.Legal and technical insights come from expertise coded into the platform, so users can see trends, the potential impact of risks, and emerging threats. It advises on possible strategies for combatting danger and vulnerabilities.The DRM also offers a “full-spectrum dispute resolution and litigation service” aimed at reducing the time needed for organisations to follow regulations and law...</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 11:13:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/cyxcel-research-discovers-a-third-of-uk-businesses-at-ai-risk/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despite Protests, Elon Musk Secures Air Permit for xAI</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/xai-data-center-air-pollution-permit/</link>
      <description>xAI’s gas turbines get official approval from Memphis, Tennessee, even as civil rights groups prepare to sue over alleged Clean Air Act violations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 23:41:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/xai-data-center-air-pollution-permit/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study finds AI can slash global carbon emissions</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/study-finds-ai-slash-global-carbon-emissions/</link>
      <description>A study from the London School of Economics and Systemiq suggests it’s possible to cut global carbon emissions without giving up modern comforts—with AI as our ally in the climate fight. According to the duo’s research, smart AI applications in just three industries could slash greenhouse gas emissions by 3.2-5.4 billion tonnes each year by […]
The post Study finds AI can slash global carbon emissions appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 16:01:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/study-finds-ai-slash-global-carbon-emissions/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Could a Healthy AI Companion Look Like?</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/tolan-chatbot-ai-companion/</link>
      <description>A chatbot designed to avoid anthropomorphism offers a compelling glimpse into the future of human-to-AI relationships.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/tolan-chatbot-ai-companion/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>These Transcribing Eyeglasses Put Subtitles on the World</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/these-translating-ai-glasses-put-subtitles-on-the-world/</link>
      <description>TranscribeGlass can subtitle conversations in nearly real time and will soon be able to translate languages and tell you when the person you’re talking to you is feeling socially awkward.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/these-translating-ai-glasses-put-subtitles-on-the-world/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How businesses can use local AI models to improve data privacy</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-businesses-can-use-local-ai-models-to-improve-data-privacy/</link>
      <description>Businesses intending to use AI do not have to rely on cloud-based tools like Chat-GPT, which tend to require uploading or sharing sensitive data. Instead, it is now possible to install and run private AI models locally, ensuring all data remains private and secure. There are several open-source tools available for those looking to experiment […]
The post How businesses can use local AI models to improve data privacy appeared first on AI News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 10:55:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/how-businesses-can-use-local-ai-models-to-improve-data-privacy/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Livestream Replay: Beginner Advice for Claude, a ChatGPT Alternative</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/subscriber-only-livestream-replay-chatbot-basics-beginner-advice-for-claude/</link>
      <description>If you missed WIRED’s live, subscriber-only Q&amp;A focused on the software features of Anthropic&#x27;s Claude chatbot, hosted by Reece Rogers and Kylie Robison, you can watch the replay here.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/subscriber-only-livestream-replay-chatbot-basics-beginner-advice-for-claude/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Pro-Russia Disinformation Campaign Is Using Free AI Tools to Fuel a ‘Content Explosion’</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/pro-russia-disinformation-campaign-free-ai-tools/</link>
      <description>Consumer-grade AI tools have supercharged Russian-aligned disinformation as pictures, videos, QR codes, and fake websites have proliferated.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 19:27:44 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/pro-russia-disinformation-campaign-free-ai-tools/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here’s What Mark Zuckerberg Is Offering Top AI Talent</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/mark-zuckerberg-meta-offer-top-ai-talent-300-million/</link>
      <description>The Meta CEO is leading a hiring blitz, offering top talent at OpenAI eye-watering pay packages and endless access to cutting-edge chips.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/mark-zuckerberg-meta-offer-top-ai-talent-300-million/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sam Altman Slams Meta’s AI Talent-Poaching Spree: &#x27;Missionaries Will Beat Mercenaries&#x27;</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/sam-altman-meta-ai-talent-poaching-spree-leaked-messages/</link>
      <description>“What Meta is doing will, in my opinion, lead to very deep cultural problems,” said OpenAI CEO Sam Altman in a leaked memo sent to OpenAI researchers.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:46:26 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/sam-altman-meta-ai-talent-poaching-spree-leaked-messages/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Videos of Black Women Depicted as ‘Bigfoot’ Are Going Viral</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/ai-videos-black-women-depicted-as-primates-viral/</link>
      <description>Some Instagram creators are using Google’s Veo 3 and racking up millions of views on AI videos of “bigfoot baddies.” They’ll teach you how to make them for $15.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:31:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/ai-videos-black-women-depicted-as-primates-viral/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flood of interest in Europe’s AI Gigafactories plan</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/flood-of-interest-in-europe-ai-gigafactories-plan/</link>
      <description>The European Commission has seen a flood of interest from companies looking to help create AI Gigafactories across Europe.Brussels has been virtually swamped with proposals for new AI Gigafactories. 76 expressions of interest have been submitted, covering 60 potential sites across 16 EU countries.The response has clearly energised officials who see it as vindication of their strategy to position Europe as a serious player in the global AI race. These aren’t just token gestures either; the proposals come from serious industry players.Major European data centre operators, telecom giants, power companies and global tech firms have all expressed interest in staking their claim in what could become Europe’s AI renaissance.While Commission officials remain tight-lipped about exactly which companies have thrown their hats into the ring – citing commercial confidentiality – the industry grapevine is already buzzing with speculation about potential consortiums forming between Europe’s tech heavyweights.Collectively, these companies are planning to snap up at least three million GPUs—providing more than enough computing muscle to train AI models that could rival or exceed anything currently available.AI Gigafactories are more than just computersSo what exactly is an AI Gigafactory? Think of it as the digital equivalent of a gargantuan manufacturing plant, but instead of churning out physical products, these facilities will develop and train the next generation of AI systems.We’re talking about computing environments of unprecedented scale. These facilities will provide the computational backbone needed for Europe to develop sovereign AI capabilities rather than relying entirely on American or Chinese technology.The Gigafactories represent an evolution of the EU’s existing AI strategy, building on the foundation laid by Europe’s already impressive EuroHPC supercomputing network. What makes them different is their singular focus on AI and their commercial orientation.Anyone following tech news knows the stakes here. The race to build advanced AI infrastructure has intensified dramatically over the past 18 months, with American tech giants investing billions in computing centres and custom chips. Meanwhile, China continues its own aggressive push into the sector.Europe’...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 16:06:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/flood-of-interest-in-europe-ai-gigafactories-plan/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloudflare Is Blocking AI Crawlers by Default</title>
      <link>https://www.wired.com/story/cloudflare-blocks-ai-crawlers-default/</link>
      <description>The age of the AI scraping free-for-all may be coming to an end. At least if Cloudflare gets its way.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wired.com/story/cloudflare-blocks-ai-crawlers-default/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power play: Can the grid cope with AI’s growing appetite?</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/power-play-can-the-grid-cope-with-ais-growing-appetite/</link>
      <description>As the AI Energy Council gathers, the question hanging in the air is: how do we power the future without blowing the grid?The massive data centres needed to train and run the latest AI are thirsty for electricity. Data centre power use in the UK is on track to multiply six times over by 2034, at which point it could be sucking up nearly a third of all our nation’s electricity. That’s a colossal strain to put on a system that was built for a completely different world, one with predictable, one-way power flows.The AI Energy Council – a team-up of tech giants, energy firms, the Ofgem regulator, and the National Energy System Operator – has the critical job of trying to predict just how thirsty this AI beast will become. Their work is happening just as the government is pouring £2 billion into its AI Opportunities Action Plan, a grand vision for weaving AI into our hospitals, classrooms, and businesses.UK Science and Technology Secretary Peter Kyle said: “Giving our researchers and innovators access to the processing power they need will not only maintain our standing as the world’s third-biggest AI power, but put British expertise at the heart of the AI breakthroughs which will improve our lives, modernise our public services, and spark the economic growth which is the cornerstone of our Plan for Change.“We are clear-eyed though on the need to make sure we can power this golden era for British AI through responsible, sustainable energy sources. Today’s talks will help us drive forward that mission, delivering AI infrastructure which will benefit communities up and down the country for generations to come without ever compromising on our clean energy superpower ambitions.”The sheer scale of the energy problem is hard to overstate. Globally, the electricity needed for data centres is expected to double in just five years, eventually demanding three times more power than the entire UK currently uses. And AI is the main culprit.A single rack of AI servers can demand 120 kW of power, a massive leap from the 5-10 kW a normal rack needs. These aren’t steady sips of power, either. AI workloads can spike unpredictably, creating sudden, massive power surges that threaten the stability of the entire grid.In response, the UK is planning a monumental overhaul. The centrep...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:53:38 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/power-play-can-the-grid-cope-with-ais-growing-appetite/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring how AI has changed daily life</title>
      <link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/exploring-how-ai-has-changed-daily-life/</link>
      <description>The impact of artificial intelligence on society continues to increase, with the technology enhancing and improving the ways in which people go about their daily lives. From carrying out mundane admin tasks to speeding up working processes, the world is more efficient thanks to AI.In recent years, the influence of AI technology has grown. Now, in 2025, it is an important tool, and it’s hard to remember what life was like before. The article will assess the many ways AI has had an impact on the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 08:49:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/exploring-how-ai-has-changed-daily-life/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>